<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc name="High Technology" image="HighTech.jpg">
<chapter name="High Tech Overview">
	<section name="Why Tactics: High Technology?" />
</chapter>
<chapter name="Cyberpunk Campaign">
	<section name="Cyberpunk Overview">
		<summary>
			* Events Leading to War
			* Overview of the War
			* Aftermath
		</summary>
	</section>
	<section name="Car Wars">
		<scenario name="Escort Duty">
			<summary>
				* An Agricorp has commissioned some independents to covertly escort an unmarked tractor-trailer 1900 miles from
				their site in La Jolla to a USDA facility near Nashville, TN.
				* A rival has sent its own independents to get their hands on the cargo.
				* Note: The cargo/escort is a decoy for the real shipment.
			</summary>
			<team name="Escort">
				<partialvictory>
					Prevent enemy from taking any of the shipment.
				</partialvictory>
				<completevictory>
					$1000/each if cargo delivered intact.
				</completevictory>
				<forces>
					* 1 Tractor-trailer
					* 2 Sedans
				</forces>
			</team>
			<team name="Interceptors">
				<partialvictory>
					Capture any of the shipment.
				</partialvictory>
				<completevictory>
					Capture the entire shipment.
				</completevictory>
				<forces>
					* 1 Van
					* 3 Sedans
				</forces>
			</team>
		</scenario>
		<scenario name="Safe House">
			<summary>
				* A small-time fixer has evidence of the identity of a cyber serial killer, the Night City Stalker.  Two news
				organizations are bidding on the deal, but the loser contacted the Stalker out of spite.
			</summary>
		</scenario>
		<scenario name="Toxic Spill">
			<summary>
				* While guarding a 200 person Nomad camp, the well drill discovers a hidden toxic waste dump.  Alarms alert the
				dumping company that their little secret has been discovered, so they send a team to 'clean up' the problem.
				* The whole Nomad camp must evacuate 3 miles to town before they are silenced, unfortunately they do not have
				enough vehicles to do it in one trip.
			</summary>
		</scenario>
		<scenario name="The Heist">
			<summary>
				* In a winter storm, a shipment of Palladium is diverted to a small warehouse in a corporate park.  It will not
				be moved until the weather turns, so it is a perfect opportunity to break in and steal the goods.
				* During the storm, the skies are dangerous, and even the roads are fairly dicey.  Snowmobile are certainly an
				option.
			</summary>
			<team name="Thieves">
				<partialvictory>
					Take at least half of the shipment.
				</partialvictory>
				<completevictory>
					Capture the whole shipment.
				</completevictory>
				<forces>
					* 10 Thieves
					* 5 Snowmobiles
					* 3 Sedans
				</forces>
			</team>
			<team name="Guards">
				<partialvictory>
					Protect at least half of the shipment.
				</partialvictory>
				<completevictory>
					Protect the entire shipment.
				</completevictory>
				<forces>
					* 10 Armed and Armored Guards
					* 10 Unarmored, sleeping Guards
					* 5 Sedans
					* 2 Helicopters
				</forces>
			</team>
		</scenario>
	</section>
</chapter>
<chapter name="High Tech Rules">
	<section name="Cyberspace">
		<titles>The Digital Web, The Net, The Network, World Wide Web, The Web</titles>
		<summary>
			* A huge, interconnected series of computer networks, software systems, and virtual realities that form a continuous
			digital universe of nearly infinite scope.
			* Interface programs sort through this information and produce a virtual world tailored to the user's desire.  The
			most common interface is that of digital cities that mirror their real world equivalents, but display computer
			systems, data blocks, and information pathways instead of buildings, people, and highways.
			* Nodes - Nodes in Cyberspace are locations in Cyberspace.  Nodes include Telecom lines, Satellite Uplinks,
			Firewalls, Security Cameras, Remote Controls, Databases, and Virtual Realities.  Different Nodes usually require
			valid security or payment to use.  Nodes can also hold nasty surprises including alarms and defense programs.
			* Movement - Distances are insignificant in Cyberspace.  Instead, movement is measured in tasks.  Any program can
			perform a number of tasks each turn equal to [Netrunning] skill.  Each node entered in Cyberspace is a task.
			Performing any [Action] at a node is also a task.
		</summary>
	</section>
</chapter>
<chapter name="High Tech Equipment">
	<section name="Consumer Goods">
		<item name="Autobike">
			<summary>
				* Autonomous motorcycle used for most transit. A small fraction of the Autocar
				fleet is filled by Autobikes. Though slightly cheaper to rent than Autocars and
				better in tight traffic, most people use Autocars exclusively.
			</summary>
		</item>
		<item name="Autocar">
			<summary>
				* Autonomous car used for most transit. Ordinary citizens rarely own their own
				vehicles, instead they summon an automated rental car with their phone that takes
				them directly to their destination. Autocars are parked throughout populated
				areas, so summoning one usually takes seconds. Autocars coordinate with each other
				and can travel at high speeds in tight traffic without incident.
				* History - Automated cars took over major cities within years of their invention.
				They solved traffic, parking, accident, and environmental problems all at once
				while offering cheaper per mile travel than owning your own vehicle. They rapidly
				made taxi and ridesharing solutions obsolete, and it soon became illegal for a
				human to drive a vehicle because autocars were so much safer. Soon all mass
				transit systems reduced down to autocars and some autobikes.
			</summary>
		</item>
		<item name="Cyberchip">
			<summary>
				* Standard memory/application chip.  All media is stored on cyberchips and can be played by simply plugging the
				chip into any standard interface.
				* Plugging cyberchips directly into one's body is called 'Chipping In'.
			</summary>
		</item>
		<item name="Cybercycle">
			<summary>
				* High performance motorcycle that allows direct neural interface.
			</summary>
		</item>
		<item name="Cyberdeck">
		</item>
		<item name="Cyberphone">
		</item>
		<item name="Direct Neural Interface">
			<summary>
				* This implant includes a processor chip and interface plugs that connect directly to the brain.  The chip
				contains an artificial intelligence avatar program that learns from and emulates the user's personality.  This
				AI can then enter cyberspace or control cybernetic equipment at the speed of a computer program while retaining
				the decision making logic of its user.  Further, the AI regularly updates the user with its decisions, and
				gathers the user's impression, so it can make further decisions.  While 'Jacked In' the user is motionless as
				his mind is overwhelmed with information from the AI.  DNI's are powerful tools, but are also risky technology.
				Since information floods into the mind at incredible speeds, any malfunction in the DNI or the AI can cause
				sanity threatening sensory overload or sensory deprivation that seem to last for days in mere seconds.
				* Burn Out - losing one's mind to DNI failure.
			</summary>
		</item>
		<item name="Flitter">
			<titles>Aerogyro, Gyrocopter</titles>
			<summary>
				* Light, one-man helicopter
			</summary>
		</item>
		<item name="Hover Board" />
		<item name="Mag Lev Train">
			<summary>
				* Speed: 200mph
			</summary>
		</item>
		<item name="Metrocar">
			<summary>
				* Ultra-subcompact reverse trike.
			</summary>
		</item>
		<item name="Mister Fusion" image="HighTech/MrFusion.jpg" />
		<item name="Quad ATV" />
		<item name="Private Quadcopter" />
		<item name="Skimmer">
			<titles>Ground Effect Vehicle, Hovercraft</titles>
			<summary>
				* The modern hovercraft creates a tightly computer-controlled air pocket beneath
				it that allows the Skimmer to move quickly over land or sea. The Skimmer
				manipulates the pocket to change direction. Though fast and all-terrain, they are
				not as quiet, maneuverable, or energy efficient as Autocars, so their use is
				limited to lightly populated areas.
			</summary>
		</item>
	</section>
	<section name="Corporate Equipment">
		<item name="Cargo Osprey">
		</item>
		<item name="Corporate Limosine" />
		<item name="Corporate Osprey">
			<summary>
				* Speed: 275knots
				* Range: 600miles
				* The Osprey is a tilt-wing propeller plane that is used as a
				corporate commuter plane. Like a helicopter, it can land on
				buildings, and it can also fly directly to nearby cities.
			</summary>
		</item>
		<item name="Personal Aerodyne">
			<summary>
				* Speed: 250mph
				* Range: 400miles
			</summary>
		</item>
		<item name="Transjet">
			<titles>Hopper, Transatmospheric Jet</titles>
			<summary>
				* The Transjet is the standard commercial airliner across the world. It flies up
				beyond the atmosphere where it can travel at extreme speeds and then lands
				anywhere in the world within an hour.
			</summary>
		</item>
	</section>
	<section name="Police Equipment">
		<item name="Aerodyne">
			<titles>Air Car, Pegasus</titles>
			<reference>Blade Runner</reference>
			<summary>
				* Speed: 350mph
				* Range: 400miles
				* Short and bulbous, the Aerodyne has the aerodynamics of a brick.  It relies on its huge jets to fly.
			</summary>
		</item>
	</section>
	<section name="Military Equipment">
		<unit name="Combat Aerodyne">
			<summary>
				* Speed: 480mph
				* Range: 600miles
				* Armored combat Aerodyne
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Barracuda Drone Submarine">
			<summary>
				* Carrier borne small, unmanned, high speed, attack submarine. It is designed as a long range drone that continually scouts the water surrounding a capital ship. Its tip is a HEAT shaped explosive, and it uses a particularly volitle fuel mix, so that it can be used as a torpedo if any serious threat enters its sphere of control.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Manta VTOL Fighter">
			<reference>
				* Carrier Command: Gaea Mission
			</reference>
			<summary>
				* Carrier borne VTOL Fighter. It has four redirectable thrusters that allow it to hover at any altitude including directly over water. It is fully sealed and can be launched and recovered underwater, but its underwater speed is poor. Its thrust is sufficient to ferry a Sea Lion ATV or other medium vehicle when necessary. It has a small, replaceable mission module to custom tailor its missions for anti-air, anti-ship, anti-armor, anti-personnel, missile, bombs, repair, apc, recon, science, transport, and more. Its mission module is interchangable with the Sea Lion Amphibious Tank.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Pelican VTOL Heavy Transport">
			<summary>
				* Land based VTOL transport plane. It has four redirectable thrusters that allow it to hover at any altitude including directly over water. It is fully sealed and can land and take off from water. It has a single landing deck on top to facilitate in-air refuelling and resupply of VTOL fighters. It has a large, replaceable mission module to custom tailor its missions for anti-air, anti-ship, anti-armor, anti-personnel, missile, bombs, repair, apc, recon, science, transport, and more. It is powerful enough to carry 1 heavy tank, 2 medium tanks, or 3 APCs. It is, however, a large target with limited armor, so it is not suitable for heavy fire situations.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Sea Lion Amphibious Medium Tank">
			<reference>
				* Carrier Command: Gaea Mission
			</reference>
			<summary>
				* Carrier borne All Terrain Vehicle. It has six wheels that work equally well on water or land, but on water it augments its speed using a caterpillar drive. It is fully sealed and submerisble, but its underwater speed is poor. It has a small, replaceable mission module to custom tailor its missions for anti-air, anti-ship, anti-armor, anti-personnel, missile, repair, apc, recon, science, and more. Its mission module is interchangable with the Manta Fighter.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Sailfin Light Frigate">
			<titles>Flying Fish</titles>
			<summary>
				* Fully Submersible Light Frigate loaded with 2 Barracuda Submarines.
				* Purpose - The Sailfin is a high speed interceptor and screening craft. It is equipped with anti-missile and small anti-ship weaponry as well as a large ECM suite.
				* Hydrofoils - Uses a Magnetohydrodynamic (MHD) to produce high speeds with little noise. It is designed in a catamaran configuration with hydrofoils and an air cushion effect to provide near flight.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Hammerhead Destroyer">
			<summary>
				* Fully Submersible Destroyer loaded with 2 Manta Fighters and 4 Barracuda Submarines.
				* Purpose - The Hammerhead is an all round escort ship for larger capital ships.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Mako Assault Carrier">
			<reference>
				* Carrier Command: Gaea Mission
			</reference>
			<summary>
				* Fully Submersible Light Carrier loaded with 4 Manta Fighters, 4 Sea Lion ATVs, and 2 Barracuda Submarines. Uses a Magnetohydrodynamic (MHD) to produce high speeds with little noise.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Orca Medium Cruiser">
			<summary>
				* Fully Submersible Medium Cruiser loaded with 6 Manta Fighters, 1 Pelican Transport, 6 Sea Lion ATVs, and
				4 Barracuda Submarines.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Leviathan Command Carrier">
			<summary>
				* Fully Submersible Heavy Carrier loaded with 12 Manta Fighters, 4 Pelican Transports, 6 Sea Lion ATVs, and
				8 Barracuda Submarines.
			</summary>
		</unit>
	</section>
	<section name="Body Armor">
		<unit name="Stealth Suit">
			<titles>Ghost Special Operative</titles>
			<reference>
				* Nuclear launch detected... - Starcraft
			</reference>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Powered Body Armor">
			<titles>Hard Suit</titles>
			<summary>
				* Heavy Body Armor
			</summary>
		</unit>
	</section>
</chapter>
<chapter name="High Tech Spacecraft">
	<summary>
		* Interplanetary travel is a common reality in the 23rd century.

		* Types - Spaceships are mostly cargo and ore mining ships, followed by gas tankers.

		* Prismatic Armor - Modern ships have a very thick ablative skin composed of a honeycomb of diamond nano-fibers filled with a highly refractive, radiation and impact absorbing ceramic compound. This armor has a number of beneficial qualities. It deflects energy in random directions which provides radiation resistance, stealth, and energy weapon defense. It fragments and ablates under energy weapon and kinetic impact which shatters incoming	micro-meteors and high speed weaponry and distributes the incoming energy in all directions to prevent penetration. The ablating particles also carry away excess heat in a similar way to evaporation. The resultant particles become a cloud of anti-energy aresol. Any impact strong enough to penetrate the armor will liquify the surrounding armor which quickly solidifies and helps to seal hull breaches.

		* Deflectors - Most long-range ships are equipped with a deflector array. The array is composed of a wide bank of closely spaced ionizing lasers and particle beams. The lasers ionize the particles and form a strong magnetic force down the length of the beam. Small objects headed toward the ship are ionized by the beams and then redirected away by the magnetic field. Point defense lasers are used for larger particles as well as incoming missiles.

		* Propulsion - Propulsion spaceward (outward from the Sun) is often provided by massive Stellasers that reflect and concentrate solar radiation into a 'tight' beam similar to a laser. Ships have depolyable solar sails to capture this energy for propulsion and recharging batteries. These sails can even be used to slowly tack inward. Some cargo ships use particularly large sails to slowly sail the solar wind to reduce costs. Most ships rely on powerful nuclear thrusters for sunward (toward the Sun) travel to accelerate the ship at up to 1g. When possible the ship will accelerate for half the voyage, turn around, and then decelerate for the rest of the trip.

		* Gravity - Except for short periods of weightlessness midway through the trip, the passengers feel gravity during the trip. Up is toward the nose and down is toward the engines. The internal organization of a ship is very similar to a skyscraper. For fuel and reaction mass reasons, the ship may need to travel at slower speeds (and lower gravity) or coast at zero gravity midway through the trip. For this reason, large ships are often equipped with rotating decks to simulate gravity for the crew.

		* Reentry - Spaceships are generally too heavy and not equipped to survive a landing on anything larger than a small moon. Landing on something as massive as the Earth's Moon is possible, but achieving orbit again requires a powerful Laser Lifter system like the one on Luna.

		* Travel Costs
		** Planet to orbital station skyhooks travel daily and cost 200-300 credits one-way.
		** Orbital to moon travel twice weekly and cost 600 credits one-way.
		** Interplanetary trips are like cruises. They travel weekly and cost 20,000-30,000 credits
		one-way.

		* Safety - Inner ship walls are covered with pillowy-soft panels of 'Space Gel'. This viscous fluid provides a combination of heat insulation, impact padding, radiation shielding, shrapnel absorption, and depressurization protection. Space Gel exposed to freezing temperatures will immediately harden into a very durable solid. If the hull is breached, damaged panels will leak Space Gel. Any gel that touches an area near the breach will instantly freeze, gradually plugging the leak.
	</summary>
	<section name="High Tech Commercial Spacecraft">
		<unit name="Shuttlecraft" />
		<unit name="Cargo Spacefreighter" />
		<unit name="Ore Spacefreighter">
			<summary>
				* Magsail ship
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Gas Spacefreighter" />
		<unit name="Space Rescue Ship">
			<reference>Event Horizon</reference>
			<summary>Emergency Medical and Rescue Craft</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Star Explorer">
			<summary>Scout Vessel</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Spaceliner">
			<titles>Starliner</titles>
			<summary>Luxury cruise liner for tourism or transport</summary>
		</unit>
	</section>
	<section name="Fighter Class">
		<unit name="Star Bomber" />
		<unit name="Star Figher">
			<summary>
				* General purpose space fighter that can be fitted with special purpose gear.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Star Interceptor" />
		<unit name="Star Torpedo Bomber" />
	</section>
	<section name="High Tech Shuttle Class">
		<unit name="Assault Shuttle" />
		<unit name="Eagle Lunar Transport" mass="238 tons" length="23m" width="9m" speed="162 Mkmh" range="26 Bkm">
			<titles>Eagle</titles>
			<summary>
				* The Eagle is the primary form of transportation for the inhabitants of the various moons of the Solar System. A multipurpose craft, it is divided into three basic sections; the command module, the service pod, and the superstructure. It is powered by four nuclear fusion rockets, and carries fuel reserves for 48 hours of flight.
				* Type A Transport Eagle is fitted with the standard passenger pod and is capable of holding 8 passengers (up to 12 in an emergency), in addition to the pilot and co-pilot.
				* Type B Freighter Eagle is used for transporting supplies, equipment and minerals. They can also be used as space-borne tankers for refueling.
				* Type C Reconnaissance Eagle comes equipped with various types of sensory devices for exploratory missions.
				* Type D Rescue Eagle, identifiable by the bold red stripes on the pod, has been adapted for field diagnosis and treatment of injury or disease. Manned by medical personnel, Rescue Eagles are equipped with mobile beds, patient-monitor units, and facilities for field surgery.
				* Type E Laboratory Eagle is equipped with a remote laboratory and can be used to locate and refine crude minerals, eliminating the need to transport bulky raw ores. It can carry food and water and recycle air to support the team for several weeks.
				* Specialty Modules include a the winch platform used to disperse nuclear waste canisters. There is also an additional booster unit that can be added to the super-structure which can increase the range and power.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Lunar Rail Capsule">
			<summary>
				* A small pod launched from a Lunar Rail Gun. Passenger Capsule are launched from 80 mile long Rail guns at 1G. Cargo capsules are launched from 2 mile long Rail guns at 40G. They are then captured in lunar orbit by drones and lunar satellite bases.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Star Gunship">
			<summary>
				* General purpose heavy weapons platform that can be fitted with special purpose gear.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Heavy Star Bomber" />
		<unit name="Reconnaissance Shuttle" />
		<unit name="Star Torpedo Boat" />
	</section>
	<section name="Frigate Class">
		<unit name="Assault Star Carrier" />
		<unit name="Missile Frigate" />
		<unit name="Siege Frigate" />
		<unit name="Star Destroyer" />
		<unit name="System Defense Corvette">
			<summary>Interplanetary Defense</summary>
		</unit>
	</section>
	<section name="High Tech Cruisers">
		<unit name="Star Battleship" />
		<unit name="Star Carrier" />
		<unit name="Star Cruiser" />
	</section>
	<section name="High Tech Dreadnoughts">
		<unit name="Super Star Battleship" />
		<unit name="Super Star Carrier" />
	</section>
	<section name="High Tech Satellites">
		<unit name="Communication Satellite" />
		<unit name="Damocles Orbital Laser" image="HighTech/DamoclesSatellite.jpg">
			<summary>
				* Orbital Laser Platform designed for strategic strikes against land targets. May also be used agaist
				large orbital targets or for asteroid defense.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="EMP Satellite">
			<titles>Goldeneye</titles>
			<reference>
				* What's it going to be, Plissken? Them or us? I shut down the third world, you win they lose. I shut
				down America, they win, you lose. The more things change, the more they stay the same. - Snake Plissken,
				Escape from LA
			</reference>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Hunter Killer Satellite">
			<titles>Battle Satellite</titles>
			<summary>
				* A combat ready satellite often masquerading as a peaceful version. Hunter Satellites act like UAV's
				quietly patrolling until their weaponry is needed, then they are disposable.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Orbital Skyhook Satellite">
			<summary>
				* Large rotating satellite in low orbit. Its purpose is to drop its kilometers long tether to dock with a [Suborbital Shuttle] and use its momentum to fling the shuttle into higher orbit. A few of these Skyhooks at different orbits can pull a shuttle all the way into high orbit. Pulling up shuttles gradually degrades the satellite's orbit, but fortunately, the same system can be used in reverse to slow orbital craft without using fuel which returns lost momentum to the Skyhook.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Solar Reflector Satellite">
			<summary>
				* These are massive, lightweight solar mirrors that can be focused for variouse purposes. They can focus light for solar farms, generate light for long nights like on the moon, generate thrust by light pressure and by heating ablative drives.
			</summary>
		</unit>
	</section>
</chapter>
<chapter name="High Tech Aircraft">
	<section name="High Tech Commercial Aircraft">
		<unit name="Hypersonic Airliner">
			<summary>
				* Suborbital passenger plane that can make intercontinental flights at Mach 5+
				* Such high speed planes are all wedge shaped Hypersonic Waveriders.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Suborbital Shuttle">
			<summary>
				* Suborbital passenger plane that can reach the upper atmosphere and connect to an [Orbital Skyhook Satellite]'s
				tether.  The end of the tether holds a small wing shaped cargo container.  Passengers and cargo are quickly
				exchanged, and the container is reeled back up to the skyhook while the plane returns to its launch site.
			</summary>
		</unit>
	</section>
	<section name="High Tech Military Aircraft">
		<unit name="Valkyrie Air Cavalry" classification="Lt. Aircraft">
			<summary>
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Aurora Transatmospheric Fighter" classification="Lt. Aircraft">
			<summary>
				* A sleek, shuttle-like jet with speeds of Mach 5. A nuclear engine, stealth armor, full environmental containment, and a virtual or direct neural link make this one-man craft the deadliest thing in the skies.
				* It carries twin 30mm autocannons, a plasma cannon, 16 air-to-air missiles, and 2 fuel air explosives for ground targets.
			</summary>
		</unit>
	</section>
</chapter>
<chapter name="High Tech Heavy Armor">
	<section name="High Mobility Forces">
		<titles>Armored Frame, Exo-Suit, MEC (Multi-Environment Cavalry), Mobile Armor, Mobile Cavalry, Mobile Invantry, Mobile Suit</titles>
		<summary>
			* Mobile - The term Mobile, short for High Mobility, was coined to describe forces that emphasized manueverability and terrain use over raw speed, weaponry, or armor.
			** Mobile Infantry - Human sized battle suits capable of increasing an infantry unit's combat ability. Early versions emphasized weapons and armor, but their high cost and attrition rate moved the focus to fast hit-and-run or blitzkreig style armor.
			** Mobile Suit - The Mobile Suit is an attempt to create a larger version of Mobile Infantry suits. They remain humanoid and can benefit from infantry tactics on a large scale. The design is a swiss army knife, capable of quickly changing and scavenging weapons and is equally suited for combat and large scale repair operations. The design does have many detractors, however, who argue that the humanoid form is not optimal for ground combat where its height makes it an easy target, air combat where it is not aerodynamic, or space combat where legs have little use.
			** Mobile Cavalry - Mobile Cavalry is any High Mobility vehicle that is optimized toward its intended enviroment: Mobile Fighters in atmosphere, Mobile Tanks on land, Mobile Subs underwater, Mobile Insects in space, etc. These system are highly specialized in contrast with the general utility of Mobile Suits. Though such designs seem more optimal, there is an argument that Mobile Suit mass production and spare part availability would ultimately win out.
			** Mobile Armor - The ultimate expression of High Mobility weapons, Mobile Armor are large, heavily armed and armored versions of Mobile Cavalry. They are terrifying monstrosities with similar reputations to the King Tiger tank in World War II. Though on paper, they seem to be the ultimate weapon, in practice their high cost and manufacturing complexity severly limited their deployment and losing even one was devastatingly costly. They can turn the tide of any battle, but were overall less effective than smaller units.
			* Linear Frame - The linear frame is a special harness that mimics the actions of the mobile suit pilot and translates them into mobile suit actions. This gives the mobile suit an uncanny agility and a strangely human grace. A trained pilot can shift the suit's center of gravity to change the armor's orientation without propellent which can substantially increase endurance and survivability.
			* Piloting - A mobile suit pilot wears a special suit and is secured to a linear frame that
			help manage the incredible g-forces that the mobile suit produces. Rookie pilots have been
			knocked unconscious or even killed by their own combat maneuvers, so extensive, specialized
			training is essential. Ace pilots seem almost superhuman in their ability to take physical
			stress without blacking out.
			* Mobile Suits vs. Capital Ships - Mobile suits have a unique ability against capital ships.
			They can land anywhere on the surface of the ship (typically outside of firing arcs) and attack
			components directly. Whenever a mobile suit on a capital ship score [Critical Hits], the player
			may look at the damage deck and choose the critical instead of choosing one at random.
			* Flight Systems - Spacecraft and Exo-Suits use a ionic plasma drive which ionizes and
			accelerates gas particles out the exhaust vents at relativistic speeds. These energized
			particles create a glowing stardust effect at the exhaust ports. These drives also function in
			atmosphere but their interaction with air creates a massive heat buildup, so they can only be
			used in short bursts like jump jets. Unusually large vents with heat dispersers can be specially
			designed for atmosphere, but these are suboptimal in space.
			* Plasma Lance - The lance is a short mobile suit melee weapon. Its firing end is a hollow
			magnetic tube lined with layers of copper leaf. When held in a specially designed hand or connector,
			a direct current from the fusion reactor transforms the copper leaf into a short ionizing plasma jet
			of incompressible copper. The lance appears as an empty weapon hilt until it fires; then it flashes
			with a brief, blinding jet that violently pierces almost any material it contacts. It is very
			effective against armor, but its uses are limited so they may only be used a few times before being
			depleted. Mobile suits will often carry multiple lances, although larger variants exist.

			Land based Mobile Suits follow these principles:
			* Maintain a low profile - Weapons are so destructive that it is much more effective to not be hit. Stay low and use cover at all times. Tracked, Wheeled, Hover and 4 legged vehicles maintain the lowest profile while still being all-terrain.
			* High mobility - Slow, predictable units are sitting ducks. Also, move in 3 dimensions to maximize mobility. This makes legs and jump jets superior to tracks and wheels.
			* Projectile weapons are more effective on the ground than in space - High caliber cannons can be mounted on land vehicles.
			* Land based Mobile Suits developed from dog-like anti-personnel hunter-killer robots. As Electromagnetic Warfare began to defeat digital circuitry, it became necessary to put soldiers back into the war machines and return to larger, more reliable analog systems.

			Space based Mobile Suits follow these principles:
			* Propellent must be expended to accelerate - a modern vehicle in space is more limited by its propellent than its fuel.
			* Arms and Legs are useful - When one part of a mobile suit is moved, it produces a counter-movement in the opposite direction. This effect can be used to adjust the mobile suit's direction without expending propellant. Thus, in zero gravity the mobile suit's arms and legs are not dead weight, but a vital component of its maneuvering system.
		</summary>
		<unit name="Piranha Mobile Armor">
			<titles>Terrapin</titles>
			<summary>
				* The current state-of-the-art space mecha is a wedge-shaped, heavily-armored stealth craft with a turreted particle cannon.
				* Armor Module - The wedge-shaped front, bottom, and sides of the craft are a single hot-swappable module for in combat maintainance. It is primarily composed of ablative, stealth armor. The armor is sharply angled to present the smallest possible angle of penetration and detection from the front.
				* Core Module - The center of the craft is a gyroscopic sphere. The gyroscope is so powerful, it is used for attitude control instead of maneuver jets.
				* Core Drone Module - Like most mobile armors, the Piranha is deployed in large packs (schools) of drones with random human piloted command units. Without a pilot, the core module can contain spare ammo or propellent.
				* Core Pilot Module - The pilot seat is enclosed in this sphere which allows the craft to turn very quickly while rotating the pilot seat separately to minimize angular momentum and G-forces. The escape hatch can be rotated to the top or the bottom of the ship to allow easy exit or connect to ship airlocks.
				* Mission Module - The top and back of the craft contain the weapon systems, propulsion, and fuel in a single hot swappable module. This entire module can be immediately replaced to customize the craft for a mission or rapidly refuel and reload.
				* Space Interceptor Module - The standard space module includes a single heavy particle beam turret and nuclear propulsion (including fuel and reaction mass).
				* Space Bomber Module - This module is identical to the Space Interceptor Modules but replaces the turret with a fixed medium railgun and 2 heavy penetrator nuclear missiles.
				* Orbital Insertion Module - Though rarely used, this module allows the ship to reach orbit from a planet's surface using chemical rockets. The module is also capable of independent re-entry so it can be refueled and reused without the main craft.
				* Atmospheric Interceptor Module - Jet engines and anti-aircraft missiles. With this module, the ship is capable of trans-atmospheric flight. Though its wedge shape is aerodynamic, it provides no lift, so it must rely on its thrust to maneuver and to remain airborne.
				* Atmospheric Bomber Module - Jet engines and precision bombs.
				* Atmospheric Close Support Module - Jet engines and a single heavy penetrator autocannon.
				* Air Cavalry Module - Dual turbine rotor systems and fuel with 2 light rail cannons for rescue and light air support.
				* Land Module - A turret pairing a heavy rail cannon with a high capacity rail machine gun. The rear houses a missile pod housing 6 indirect fire missiles for light bombardment.
				* Marine Module - Marine caterpillar thrust system that allows high speed surface movement or moderate underwater movement with decent stealth.
				* Command Module - Advanced communications and coordiation systems.
				* Sensor Module - Specialized long-range active and passive sensor systems for patroling or spying.
				* Stealth Module - Enhanced stealth system foregoing firepower and performance for stealth. Contains a single medium rail cannon.
				* Science Module - Highly sensitive sensor package for detailed analysis.
				* Service Module - The ship has useful carrying capacity, so besides its combat role, it operates as a repair worker bee and cargo hauler. Typically, repair crews get more flight time on the ship than combat pilots.
				* Cargo Module - A large cargo container and thruster can be afixed to the rear for transport duties.
				* Long Range Module - A variant of the cargo container can be attached to the back of another module to increase the range of the ship providing extra thrust and reaction mass. The module is jettisoned once it reaches its target and is hopefully recovered later.
				* Arms - 6 thin, light-weight arms fold out from under the ship to the front, back, and sides. Each arm has 3 powerful fingers with magnetic clamps and sharp tips that allow the craft to cling to surfaces and walk along them at high speeds like an insect. The arms are strong enough to climb vertical surfaces or be inverted under gravity. The end of each arm has an attitude control jet to aid in high speed manuevers. On land, these jets are replaced with powerful turbines that lets the craft skate across level ground or water. The elbow of each arm is a sphere that can be used as landing gear or wheels on roads or other reasonably flat terrain. 6 arms were chosen, so the craft can still move on 4 arms while carrying or dragging a heavy load with 2. As with insects, 6 arms provides sufficient redundancy in case 1 or even 2 legs are lost to damage. In land combat, the arms allow the craft to maximize cover and peek its gun around corners or over obstacles.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Panther Mobile Cavalry">
			<summary>
				* The current state-of-the-art land mecha is a 4 legged style reminiscent of big cats or wolves.
				* Like most mobile armors, the Panther operates in packs of drones with random human piloted command units. The pilot climbs into the back of the unit and rides in the position of a performance motorcycle.  If desired, the pilot can open the back and sit up as if riding a horse. Piloted units sacrifice a hardpoint to fit the pilot.
				* Payloads such as large caliber cannons and shields are mounted on one of two fixed back mounts. This unit can also stand on 2 legs and slide the cannon up to become a shoulder mount. All 4 legs possess manipulative hands with claws and magnets for climbing and can carry the cannon or a shield as needed. Small wheels in the elbows are used when travelling on roads.
			</summary>
		</unit>
	</section>
	<section name="High Tech Land Vehicles">
		<unit name="Hover Tank" />
		<unit name="Light Walker" />
		<unit name="Heavy Walker" />
	</section>
</chapter>
<chapter name="Space Colonies">
	<section name="L5 Colonies">
		<titles>Orbitals, Orbital Platforms</titles>
		<summary>
			* The L5 Colonies are enormous space colonies that have been constructed at the five Lagrange points around Earth where gravitational forces are stable. They are 25km to 40km long.
			* Construction - These stations are constructed inside cylinders of Moon rock and asteroids ferried from the Asteroid Belt. The external surface is heavily armored against meteorite impacts. Industrial complexes are mostly on outermost layer of the colonies to keep them away from habitations. Towns are built on the internal surface of the colony. The internal space is divided into zones with large reflective pressure walls that give the appearance of continuous space while limiting the risk of catastrophic failure to any particular zone. Transport tubes are underground and also serve as emergency shelters. In addition to the outer cylinder, there is also an inner cylinder that forms a pressurized, zero-g drydock through the center of the colony.
			* Personnel - Those that have travelled from Earth to the Orbital stations are many of the best and brightest that Earth has to offer. Each colony supports up to 20 million people. Living space is about 300 square km, which is not a lot of room for so many people. Three or four story buildings are the norm, but they cannot be built higher than that because of the Coriolis effect.
			* Resources - Large amounts of solar energy are continuously collected, but life is difficult in space where all materials must be imported (at high tariffs). Orbital industry is generally thriving.
			* Politics - Because the Orbitals are largely corporate run and lack a specific history, they are largely free of geopolitical politics, as well as cultural and racial conflicts. They do, however, retain fierce, corporate politics. Most of all, the Orbitals chafe under the Earth bound regulatory and military agencies that supervise and tax them. Taxes are necessarily high to support so much technology, and taxes are always a point of conflict.
		</summary>
		<unit name="L1: Shangri-la" />
		<unit name="L2: Elysium" />
		<unit name="L4: Avalon">
			<summary>
				The first of the L5 colonies, Avalon has the largest starship construction facilities. Its proximity
				to Earth and the Moon provide it optimal security and resources.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="L3: Eden" />
		<unit name="L5: Valhalla" />
	</section>
	<section name="Nomad Colonies">
		<summary>
			* Small individual colonies are beginning to dot open space between the planets. These colonies maintain their own solar orbits and can be convenient stop over points between planets.
			* Culture - Nomad colonists are a hard working, individualistic people. Some are religious or cultural fanatics. Others are essentially criminal organizations or pirates. Nomad colonists are highly desired as crew for interplanetary commercial space flights. They are used to cramped space conditions and they are also 	talented mechanics and jury-riggers.
			* Trade - Each Nomad Colony is primarily a trading station. They do not produce anything except food for themselves. Everything else is purchased from other planets.
			* Politics - Nomad Colonies are each formed for their own reasons and maintain unique governments and social structures. They attempt to remain neutral from other nations and will trade with anyone without regard to political or criminal status. Though the Nomad colonies are each completely unique, they all recognize the other Nomads as allies and treat any threat to one as a threat to all.
			* Military - Nomad Colonies typically maintain little or no defenses as befits their neutral status. They may, however, maintain hidden defenses or pirate ships nearby.
		</summary>
	</section>
	<section name="Mars Colonies">
		<summary>
			* Colonial Mars is much like the American Frontier. Colonists left the overcrowded and impoverished Earth in search of a new life knowing that there was almost no chance to return to the Old World. They and their children would live or die on Mars, and they proudly adopted the name Martian.
			* Terraforming - Mars is one of the greatest technological projects ever attempted by humanity.
			* Climate - Mars is in the later stages of Terraforming. The air is thin and cold but breathable, similar to a mountain top.
			* Cities - Since the atmosphere became breathable, the population on Mars has sharply increased. Cities that were once domed habitats have grown into large settlements. Land is practically free, so buildings are low and sprawling.
			* Production - Mining is the primary reason for founding the Martian colony and continues to be the main source of jobs. Terraforming, industrial equipment, and algae farming support the mining effort.
			* Politics - The Martian Council is a democratic body that establishes and enforces Martian law. Unfortunately, they are largely a puppet of the Earth Authority and have been increasingly squeezing the Martian colonists to increase production for their war efforts. This pressure has spurred the creation of the Free Mars Movement that seeks to free Mars form Earth control.
			* Corporations - Martial Metals is one of the biggest corporations in the Solar System. It developed the orbital elevator and its steady source of cheap metals feed a large industry of orbital facilities including drydocks.
		</summary>
		<unit name="Orbital Elevator">
			<summary>
				* The Orbital Elevator is a miracle of technology and the only practical way to affordably get materials off the planet. The Orbital Elevator, the Asteroid Belt, and the Lunar Railguns are the only sources of building materials for colonies and spacecraft.
				* The Elevator is also a majestic symbol of power for the Martian Council and the Earth Authorities.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Free Mars Radical">
		</unit>
		<unit name="Martian Pirate">
		</unit>
		<unit name="Sand Marauder">
		</unit>
	</section>
	<section name="Moon Colonies">
		<titles>Lunars, Lunatics, Moon Men, Moonies, Selenites</titles>
		<summary>
			* The Moon's mineral and ice deposits made it the logical location of the first
			permanent off-world colony. Robotic solar-powered laser drills cut tunnel
			complexes into the walls of craters. Human colonists followed soon after.
			Regular exercise in 1 G training centers is mandatory for all colonists to avoid
			the dangers of low gravity.
			* Cities dot the lunar landscape connected by underground transport tubes.
			* The two largest cities maintain spaceports complete with Laser Lifters to boost large
			ships into orbit.
		</summary>
	</section>
	<section name="Solar Colonies">
		<place name="Stellaser">
			<titles>Starlight Express</titles>
			<summary>
				* Giant mirrors placed in pairs in Solar orbit. The mirrors gather light by reflecting it back and forth between them before releasing it in a concentrated beam to slowly accelerate starships. Though this beam would certainly be deadly to humans, the beam is only dangerous to exposed targets without sufficient radiation shielding.
			</summary>
		</place>
	</section>
	<section name="Venusiau Colonies">
	</section>
	<section name="Asteroid Colonies">
		<place name="Asteroid Mining Colony">
		</place>
		<unit name="Asteroid Miner">
			<titles>Belter</titles>
		</unit>
	</section>
	<section name="Jupiter Colonies">
		<summary>
			* Culture - Personal space in Jovian colonies is extremely limited, so people
			share quarters with multiple people. There are not even enough beds for each
			person, so most people live with people who work different shifts and use the
			same beds on off-shifts. Common areas are used for everything except sleeping.
			The Jovians have adapted to be far more social and reliant on others for day
			to day life. This communal living has generally made them a tight knit society
			with a strong sense of group identity.
			* Science - Jovian science is one of the most advanced in the solar system.
			Research and development on ways to make their harsh life safer and more
			comfortable are always high priorites. Jovian scientists crank out a steady
			stream of innovations across all disciplines.
			* Military - The military has reaped the rewards of Jovian science and is
			arguably the most advanced force in the solar system, though certainly nowhere
			near the largest. Jovian forces are composed of separate standing armies:
			Alpha, Beta, and Gamma Divisions with Alpha containing the Godsfire flagship.
			Jovian military theory is based on efficient use of a small number of highly
			mobile units. They do not fear a large scale assault, since they would receive
			much forewarning of any attempt to mobilize a large force all the way out to
			Jupiter. Jupiter's remoteness makes it fairly easy to defend against direct
			assault, but the harsh environment makes sabotage a much greater threat, so
			Jovian intelligence forces constantly search for threats.
			* Agora - The Jovian governing body with primary offices on Elysee colony.
		</summary>
		<place name="Elysee Station">
			<summary>
				* The largest Jovian Colony and the capital of the Jovian Confederation.
			</summary>
		</place>
		<place name="Joshua Station">
			<titles>Wildest Place in the Solar System</titles>
			<summary>
				* The second largest Jovian Colony and Jupiter's hub of manufacturing. The
				station is essentially a giant factory with live in workers. All commercial
				starships are constructed here.
				* Jovian Armor Works - The best known aerospace corporation in Jovian space
				is famous for inventing the Exo-armor and designing almost all of the
				Exo-armor fleet.
				* Joshua station also houses the seedier areas of Jovian society. Black
				markets, drug dens, and bordellos operate freely. Jovians tend to have a
				live and let live attitude, so little effort is made to stop activities that
				don't threaten the colony.
			</summary>
		</place>
		<place name="Khannan Station">
			<summary>
				* The third largest Jovian Colony and Jupiter's military center. The
				station only allows military personnel on board. Large sections of the colony
				are dedicated to ship construction and others are top secret research labs.
			</summary>
		</place>
		<place name="Jovian Gas Refinery">
			<summary>
				* These heavily armored, refining stations float in the upper atmosphere of
				Jupiter. They float by means of enormous rings filled with heated hydrogen
				and manuever using fusion thrusters. Multiple kilometer long tubes hang from
				the bottom of the station extracting gases from the differnt layers of the
				atmosphere. The broad round floatation disc and long tubes give the stations
				the general appearance of a jelly fish.
			</summary>
		</place>
		<place name="Io Colony">
			<reference>Outland</reference>
			<summary>
				* A small, titanium mining colony is located on Io. Miners work intensely to
				gain maximum bonuses. Life is dangerous and many miners are hooked on
				amphetimines to maximize productivity. Victimless crime is largely ignored
				in this generally lawless outpost. Besides miners and transport workers there
				are only cooks, bartenders, prostitutes, a single doctor, a sheriff and two
				deputies.
			</summary>
		</place>
	</section>
	<section name="Saturn Colonies">
		<summary>
			* With the exception of Titan, the outer planets are too remote and unimportant
			to ever be colonized. Jupiter provides an unlimited supply of gas resources, so
			Saturn, Uranus, and Neptune have little to offer.
		</summary>
		<place name="Titan Research Station">
			<summary>
				* A small, permanent research colony has been erected on Titan to study its
				unique atmosphere and geology. The hope was to discover evidence of primitive
				life, but no life has yet to be discovered.
			</summary>
		</place>
	</section>
</chapter>
<chapter name="Car Wars">
</chapter>
<chapter name="Cyberpunk">
	<summary>
		* The year is 2151.

		Things are pretty bad on planet Earth:
		* Global Warming - The build up of smothering greenhouse effect gases has resulted in the complete melting of the Arctic
		ice cap as well as much of the Antartic ice cap.  Coastal areas have been inundated and global temperatures continue to
		rise, a new record every year.
		* Resource Depletion - As the climate changed, desperate farmers overfarmed their land, increasing erosion and therefore
		food prices.  Fossil fuels became increasingly scarce and given the ongoing climate problems, ecologically unsuitable.
		* Overpopulation -
		* Economic Collapse -

		Things are slightly better in space:
		* Orbital Stations - For the last hundred years, large space colonies have been constructed at the five Lagrange points
		around Earth.  Relative to Earth, the Orbital stations are gleaming paradises of corporate efficiency.  Corporate
		interests are certainly strong on the Orbital colonies, and the Orbitals increasingly chafe at Earth's taxation of their
		goods and the high tariffs on imports.
		* Luna - Huge moon bases dot the lunar surface.  With its low gravity and limitless lunar rock, the Moon is the natural
		construction center for most Orbital facilities and spaceships.  Surface and underground mining operations go around the
		clock.  Enormous massdrivers propel the material into Earth orbit.
		* Mercury - Solar stations on Mercury provide limitless power while the molten
		surface provides limitless ore. Though the surface is hellish and survival is
		difficult, Mercury provides wealth beyond imagining to those able to survive.
		The population is 90% male with most residents on a 6 year work contract. After
		the contract they usually return to wherever they came from with enough money to
		buy a house and start a family. Like a military veteran, Mercury companies also
		offer generous benefits for the rest of the contractor's life or generous death
		benefits to their family if they don't survive. Despite extensive safety systems,
		the fatatlity rate remains 1 in 20 even among these hardy folk. Politically,
		Mercury is extremely independent and has little patience for the affairs of the
		other planets.
		* Venus
		* Mars
		* Asteroid Belt - Though Luna provides a steady supply of material to the colonies, whole Asteroids can be ferried from
		the Asteroid Belt to create instant colonies.  Further, the valuable minerals in an asteroid are easier to detect and
		mine than in either Lunar or Terrestrial mines.  The Asteroid field is large, however, so a whole crop of freelance
		prospectors have travelled to the Asteroid Belt in a high-tech gold-rush.
		* Jupiter
		* Saturn

* Cryomax - Maximum security prison where prisoners are stored in partial cryonic suspension to maximize space.
** Reference - Demolition Man
* Crystal - Liquid crystal computer matrix
	</summary>
	<section name="Government">
		<unit name="Innovator">
			<reference>Appleseed, Genetic Android, Bioroid</reference>
			<summary>
				* Genetically engineered artificial human.

				Theoretically superior to humans in every way, they are purposely implanted
				with a number of limitations:
				* They cannot reproduce.
				* They must undergo routine medical treatments or their genetic structure
				breaks down.
				* They are peaceful in nature to buffer mankind's tendency to violence.
				* They defer to human authority unless they believe that the authority will
				harm mankind.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Cycle Police">
			<skill name="Driving" level="4">
				<specialty name="Motorcycles" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="E.S.W.A.T.">
			<reference>Appleseed</reference>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Mobile Police">
			<reference>Appleseed</reference>
		</unit>
	</section>
	<section name="Military">
		<unit name="Combat Android">
		</unit>
		<unit name="Planetary Defense Navy">
		</unit>
		<unit name="Planetary Defense Pilot">
		</unit>
		<unit name="Eugenic Warrior">
			<titles>Master Race, Super Soldier</titles>
			<reference>
				* Khan, Star Trek II
			</reference>
			<summary>
				* Through bioengineering, an elite warrior caste has been created combining strategic genius, leadership skills,
				and physical perfection.  Unfortunately, they also develop incredible egos and megalomania.
			</summary>
		</unit>
	</section>
	<section name="MegaCorps">
		<summary>
			* After the world stock market crash and subsequent collapse of many economies and governments around the
			world (including the US), only international corporations were left with the ability to exert power on a
			global scale.
			* The economic collapse acted as a purge, the strongest conglomerates consuming the weaker ones until only
			the biggest and strongest remained. With most governments enfeebled and the competition obliterated, the
			megacorps were left to fill a huge power vacuum. Naturally there was some disagreement as to how to divide
			the spoils. The result was a series of wars as each corporation attempted to destroy its competition
			physically and finacially. Smaller conflicts, covert and overt, continue to this day, with full scale war
			threatening to resurface at any time.
		</summary>
		<unit name="Corporate Man">
			<titles>Collarboy, Company Man, Suit</titles>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Corporate Security">
		</unit>
		<unit name="System Administrator">
			<titles>Cyber Engineer, Icemen, SysOp, SysAdmin, Weasel</titles>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Kildren Pilot">
			<summary>
				* Kildren are genetically modified before birth to halt the aging process.
				Physically, they are eternally teenagers. Mentally, however, they are quiet
				and serious. A side effect of their frozen aging process is the inability to
				recall distant memories. Kildren, therefore, lack a strong sense of time or
				the past. They live for the now and are fearless pilots. For some, however,
				the sense of timelessness lacks purpose and turns into hopelessness.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Media">
			<summary>
				* Ethnicity: Greek-American
				* Hair: Black Short Waved Hair
				* Eyes: Pale Grey
				* Clothes: Clean White Shirt under black leather thigh-length light-armored jacket (occasional loose tie), grey hardwearing slacks, black shoes or running sneakers, Aviator sunglasses when being 'too cool'.
				* Equipment: Beeper, Camera, Colt automatic pistol and shoulder holster, 1 room apartment
				* Contacts: Camera Man, Police Officer
			</summary>
			<skill name="Persuasion" level="5" />
			<skill name="Communications" level="5">
				<ability name="Streetwise" />
				<ability name="Photography" />
			</skill>
			<skill name="Firearms" level="4">
				<summary>Pistol</summary>
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Medical Technician">
			<titles>Med Tech</titles>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Scientist">
		</unit>
	</section>
	<section name="Offworld Colonies">
		<unit name="Miner" />
		<unit name="Pirate" />
	</section>
	<section name="Sprawls">
		<titles>Dirtboys, Dirtgirls</titles>
		<unit name="Bounty Hunter" />
		<unit name="Cyber Psycho">
			<titles>Buttonhead</titles>
			<summary>
				* Buttonhead - someone addicted to artificially stimulating the pleasure centers of the brain.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Enforcer" />
		<unit name="Fixer">
			<titles>
				Bookie, Executive Secretary, Gobetween, Information Broker, Negotiator, Organizer, Producer, Roadie, Thirdman
			</titles>
			<summary>
				* Fixers buy and sell information, goods, and services.
				* Some of their services merely require the right connections.  Others are not quite legal.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Gang Member" />
		<unit name="Netrunner">
			<titles>Crystaljock, Hacker</titles>
			<summary>
				* Outlaw computer jocks or hackers.  Some people do it for the glory; most do it for the money.  Information is
				power in the modern world and all the information is somewhere on the Net.  Further, the modern world is a marvel
				of automation, so a clever person may turn that automation to his own uses.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Nomad">
			<titles>Deltajock, Gypsy, Linerunner, Panzerjock, Road Warrior, Smuggler</titles>
			<summary>
				* Deltajock - A pilot of delta-winged smuggling craft
				* Panzerjock - A driver of armored smuggling hovercraft
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Rocker">
			<titles>Bard</titles>
			<summary>
				* Zonedancing - Dancing turned into a dominance game.  A dancer attempts to persuade other dancers in his zone to
				conform to his movements using charisma, talent or violence.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Solo">
			<titles>Assassin, Hit Man</titles>
			<reference>
				* I don't want to walk this Earth if I gotta do it solo...so...low. - Iyaz, Solo
			</reference>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Tech">
			<titles>Cybertech</titles>
		</unit>
	</section>
</chapter>
<chapter name="Jovian Chronicles">
	<section name="Orbital Revolution">
		<summary>
			Events Leading to War
			* Air Tax

			Overview of the War
			* Rock War

			Aftermath
			* Terran Union
		</summary>
		<scenario name="Rock War">
		</scenario>
		<scenario name="Battle in the Depths">
			<summary>
				* An undersea fission cannon is discovered before it becomes operational.
				* A squadron is sent ahead of the fleet to destroy the cannon before it
				is brought to bear on the fleet.
				* The base defenders need to stall for 10 minutes until the cannon can be
				fired destroying most of the fleet. 5 minutes later a second shot will
				ensure victory.
				* The battle takes place completely underwater.
			</summary>
		</scenario>
		<scenario name="Destroy the Downlink">
			<summary>
				* The rebels choose to destroy a microwave receiver converting power from
				a vast orbital solar satellite array. If they can destroy it, the entire
				area will be without power and defenseless for days allowing the rebels
				free reign to take territory.
				* The defenders realize the vulnerability of the station and it is
				heavily defended.
			</summary>
		</scenario>
		<scenario name="Rat Warren">
			<summary>
				* The mechs stationed to defend the city are cut off from reinforcements.
				* The rebels see an opportunity, but they have only powersuits and their
				wits to take the colossal defenders down. They can use the sewers and
				subways as cover to launch hit and run attacks.
			</summary>
		</scenario>
		<scenario name="Traitorous Acts">
			<summary>
				* An surprise attack is launched on a munitions depot, but there is a
				problem. The defenders are not surprised: there is a mole in your group.
				* Attackers have a superior force, but one of them is a traitor. They
				will have to watch their backs.
				* Defender secretly chooses one attacking unit as the traitor and can
				choose to activate it at any time.
			</summary>
		</scenario>
		<scenario name="Joy Ride">
			<summary>
				* A young, hotshot rebel manages to sneak into an enemy test facility and
				steal a prototype mecha. The whole base is on his tail, and he will need
				to use urban cover and speed to try to get away.
			</summary>
		</scenario>
		<scenario name="Train Spotting">
			<summary>
				* Ambush a mag-lev train and stop it before it escapes.
				* Attackers must disable the train and destroy the defenders.
				* Defenders must escape or drive off the attackers.
			</summary>
		</scenario>
		<scenario name="Breaking Damocles">
			<summary>
				* The Damocles is an orbital facility equipped with a powerful laser. Its
				existence has put major pressure on Earth governments to comply with UEA
				demands.
				* Attackers must placed explosives along the edge of the facility and
				destroy the attitude control thrusters to send the facility into a death
				spiral that would make it burn up in orbit. Hopefully, it will crash in
				an uninhabited area.
				* Defenders must destroy the attackers or the explosives to prevent this
				nightmare scenario.
			</summary>
		</scenario>
		<scenario name="Moon Rocket">
			<summary>
				* A huge rocket is about to be launched from its silo in a crater on the
				Moon.
				* The attackers must destroy the launch silo or failing that the missile
				itself before it leaves the combat area. Critical hits on the missile
				may cause it to explode, destroying the launch base.
			</summary>
		</scenario>
		<scenario name="Mirage Storm">
			<summary>
				* Two recon mechs gather intelligence around Jupiter but are pursued. The
				recon units try to even the odds by flying into the atmosphere directly
				into a super storm. The storm plays havoc with normal sensors, but the
				recon units can sort out the jumble of sensor data.
				* The 5 attackers must destroy the 2 escaping mechs.
				* The defenders must drive off or destroy the superior attackers.
				* Special Rules: For each defender place 2 additional ghost mechs on the
				battlefield. These represent false image data produced by the cloud.
				After each attack, the defenders may secretly switch which unit is
				the real mech among the three identical images. The ghost mechs are
				obviously immune to all damage.
			</summary>
		</scenario>
	</section>
	<section name="Jovian Odyssey">
		<scenario name="Dreams OF Phantoms">
			<summary>
				* Call of Jupiter - Jovian scientists discovered an odd life form floating in Juptier's
				atmosphere, the Jovian Floater. A floating research station was proposed, but the
				extreme funding could not be secured. Spies for the Venusian Bank determined that the
				Floaters may be responsible for the phenomenon called the 'Call of Jupiter', where
				explorers to Jupiter have often explained that they were drawn to Jupiter because of
				dreams they had of Jupiter singing to them. This would imply that the Floaters can
				communicate telepathically over interplanetary space: an incredible finding.

				* Slumbering Eidolon - The Venusians established a top secret floating base in Jupiter's
				atmosphere under the noses of the Jovians. The intense atmosphere combined with the
				powerful radiation and magnetic fields effectively hide them from any watching eyes
				above. Eidolon is secretly supported by a group in the largely lawless Joshua Station
				to procure or ship supplies and provide emergency rescue if necessary.

				* Mission - Discover the Slumbering Eidolon and capture or destroy it. They could
				discover it by finding a supply or courier ship headed there during a patrol, or stumble
				across a supporting organization on a Jovian colony. The assault force would
				most probably consist of two Thunderbolts, one Javelin, and a small number of
				Pathfinders and Retaliators. If they choose to capture the Eidolon, a hurried scramble
				as a self-destruct timer counts down and bulkheads slam shut is just as exciting as an
				action-packed firefight in the command center. Agents and reporters are harder to
				integrate with the destruction of the station, but are more
				easily involved in the discovery process.
			</summary>
		</scenario>
		<scenario name="Dreams OF Secrets">
			<summary>
				* Summary - After the discovery and decomissioning of the secret Venusian research
				station, the Jovian government found some advanced mech prototypes that the Venusians
				had been testing in the Jovian atmosphere. This led to the Agora paying more attention
				to a request of assylum from one Dr. Peyarje, and sent the PCs to help retrieve him.

				* Dr. Peyarje - UEA has conscripted the brilliant Dr. Peyarje into their service,
				forcing him to develop next generation exo-weapons at a hidden base. In the interests of
				keeping an appearance of openness, they have allowed Peyarje to attend the 2210
				 Intersettlement Scientific Convention (ISC), though he is accompanied by a detachment
				of the UEA military. He has managed to get a plea for help and request for asylum to the
				Jovian embassy. His crowning achievement is a telepathic mech control system based on
				discoveries found from the Floaters over Jupiter.

				* Georgia On My Mind - The players have been dispatched to extract Peyarje from the ISC
				conference in Venus orbit. They are hidden among the large Jovian delegation to the ISC
				aboard the Georgia On My Mind space liner. However, in order to smuggle them aboard,
				they can carry now weapons or equipment and will need an alternate means of escape.

				* Stanton Station - A space station in Venus Orbit where the Internation Scientific
				Convention (ISC) is being held. Here, Peyarje will be allowed to present a carefully
				censored summary of his work on cyberlinkage technologies. The players should take part
				in the early stages of the ISC while they investigate the conference and find a way to
				get Peyarje away from his UEA handlers and off-station.

				* Jovians - The Jovians wish to reap the PR benefits to be found in rescuing a brilliant,
				pacifist scientist from UEAs militaristic clutches and also hope that Peyarje can shed
				some light on some samples of his CAT/Rapid-Scan system found on a secret research
				station.

				* UEA - Unfortunately for these operatives, the UEA is taking the security of their
				prisoner very seriously. The third division of the UEA 4th fleet are moored just off
				Stanton, at the invitation of the Venusian Plantary Council, and permission has been
				granted for several officers and marines to accompany Peyarje as a security detail.
				Though the ISC filed a formal protest over the admittance of UEA military officers
				acting in an official capacity, the issue has since been dismissed and other nations
				have been allowed to included similarly-limited security details for their detachments.

				* Beautiful Dreamer - The PC's meet their contact, Ysa Cantroini and through her, Aglaee
				Dessources. Both seem to be independents commissioned by the Jovians. Ysa is surpisingly
				competent at many abilities and Aglaee has a ship for escape along with the  characters'
				gear and mechs.


* CHARACTER INVOLVEMENT
JAF pilots could be members of an official JAF escort, added (as mentioned
above) to balance out the UEA military forces escorting Dr. Peyarje. The pilots would still be
instructed to ask questions and discretely investigate, but would be intended to act as a decoy
and backup for the real extraction team. By asking questions and poking their noses into places
they dont belong, they would be expected to draw attention away from the real JIS operatives.
Who could, in turn, be exposed and captured at the last minute, forcing the players to pull off
the heist on their own with insufficient planning.

The players could be the backup JIS team instead of the primary, tasked with investigating and
doing footwork for the primary team. This puts them on the front lines, while the primary team
works to solidify their own cover. The primary teams cover could then be blown, forcing the
players to execute the operation, and keeping them on the front lines. This has many hooks for
complications and intruigue. What if the compromised team wasnt discovered, but betrayed
by a double agent in their own ranks? This goes well with the scenario (see below) that has
the players trapped in hiding on Stanton. What if the Venusians (specifically, Malachai) were
aware of the operation all along and either want the operatives to expose themselves or for the
operation to succeed/fail for reasons of their own?

Reporters have the easiest time finding cover identities - they dont need them. The ISC is a big
deal, and reporters from all over the solar system can be expected to attend. And reporters are
expected to be nosy, so no-ones going to take excessive notice of a few asking questions where
they shouldnt. However, due to their typical lack of combat skills, reporters will probably be harder
to handle for the actual freeing of Peyarje. They would probably have to resort to subterfuge and
trickery if called upon to get Peyarje away from his guards themselves. One possibility is to have
JIS agents already in place on Stanton handle the snatch, then pass Peyarje off to the reporters
for transport, as in the JAF pilots write-up above.

The 3rd Division of the CEGA 4th fleet is composed of:
  2 Tengu carriers with extra vehicle bays.
  4 Bricru corvettes.
  1 Hachiman destroyer.

One Tengu carries a Wyvern and three Wraiths, while the other carries four Syreens. The
squadron is accompanied by several fuel ships, to give extra range to the short-legged CEGA
warships. Garands Wyvern is the Command variant. While the Hachiman is technically the
flagship of the squadron, Garand usually commands from aboard his Tengu where he has easy
access to his exo-armor. This can be used to involve Kleb in the scenario without Garands
knowledge - Kleb could be travelling aboard the Hachiman, watching and ready to take command
should the situation demand it.

				* Escape - The 3rd Divison lacks is deployed far from reinforcements, so it will act
				cautiously. They know that they dont need to kill the players - they need to capture
				the Dreamer. The PCs should realize this, and be careful not to let themselves be drawn
				away... For what seems like a retreat could really be an attempt to lure them away so
				that another force can slip in and disable the Dreamers engines.
			</summary>
		</scenario>
		<scenario name="Dreams oF Freedom">
			<summary>
				* Beautiful Dreamer - Rescued from his UEA handlers at the Intersettlement Scientific
				Convention, Dr. Peyarje and his rescuers have fled Venus aboard the Beautiful Dreamer,
				privateer ship commanded by Aglaee DesSources. Unfortunately, they have not lost the UEA
				forces seeking to recapture Peyarje. The 3rd Division of the UEA 4th fleet, commanded
				by ace pilot Ranho Garand, is in hot pursuit.

				* Intercept Course - DesSources skillful helmsmanship makes the most of their limited
				reaction mass, but Garands 3rd Division is slowly closing in, blocking the orbits they
				could use to travel out-system. Garand's fleet makes a high energy burn and manages to
				intercept them and another heated battle ensues. After the battle, the UEA force, having
				used their remaining reaction mass to intercept must wait for a fuel tender to continue
				the pursuit.

				* The Long Trip to Earth - Low on fuel, with the UEA pursuit fleet closing in fast, the
				crew of the Beautiful Dreamer find themselves with only one option: change course and
				head for the Earth system, the heart of the UEA and the only source of supplies and fuel
				in range. Perhaps they can loose their pursuers in the high-traffic Orbitals and find
				another way to Jupiter. Because reaction mass is low and they need to run silent, the
				trip takes many days at zero-g. Many days in radio silence are spent discussing ways to
				get out of this mess.
			</summary>
		</scenario>
		<scenario name="Moonlight Sonata">
			<summary>
				* Ismael Li - Fortunately, the Jovians have been working hard to save the mission and
				have made a deal with a burgeoning rebel group on the Moon which can to provide them
				with the fuel and parts they need... For a price!

				* The Eagle has Landed - Now they just need to avoid the blockade and land on the Moon.
				Though the Moon has very low gravity, the Beautiful Dreamer is not designed to land on
				a Moon. Even if they survive the landing, they may not be able to take off again.
				However, there is no choice in the matter. After a harrowing landing, the rebels help
				bury the Dreamer in lunar dust and begin repairs and refueling.

				* Copernicus Base - The characters are invited to the underground, domed city known as
				Coperinus Base. Here the charismatic Ismael Li introduces them to the harsh life of
				the Lunar miners. There is nothing to do but wait and meet the pleasant locals while the
				ship is repaired and the UEA prepares its next move.

				* The Plot Thickens - Gradually, Ismael brings the characters to see supporters and see
				his gear. Ismael intends to lead a rebellion to take over Copernicus Base and he needs
				the characters' help. His group lacks seasoned fighters and they lack tactics,
				organization, and strategy. This revelation sparks a heated debate over the wisdom of
				this endevour. No one can argue that their situation is difficult, but even if they
				succeed the Lunar Authority and the UEA will not just sit back and allow a rebellion.
				Ismael argues that once they seize control, the Lunar Authority will have to negotiate.
				Others fear a strong, military response. Any armed conflict in a space station is
				loaded with risk. If one of the characters befriends or falls in love with one of the
				rebels, it would add a more personal edge to the rebellion.

				* Eleventh Hour - With or without the characters' help, Ismael begins to grease the
				wheels of revolution through raids, assassinations, sabotage, and public relations
				campaigns. Their target is Captain Ansevik the head of Copernicus security. If they
				can capture her, they believe they can secure the base.

				* Moon Strike - After providing the characters with the repairs and fuel they need, he
				launches his armed uprising in the depths of Copernicus hoping to drag them into the
				fight. Moving barricades outwards at carefully-regulated intervals, his troops and
				exo-suits advance through the dome, driving out the UEA bureaucrats and policemen as
				they go. The few initial firefights go well for the rebels.

				* The Tide Turns - About six hours into the fighting, things begin to turn. Ansevik
				manages to get her exo-suit forces into Copernicus, and their numbers mean bad things
				for the rebels.

				* Evacuation - Catherine Glit starts an evacuation of refugees. The rebels lift as many
				to hastily-contracted merchant and passenger ships in lunar orbit as they can. Things
				become even more chaotic as the Selenties abandon their posts and the rebels fall back
				before the UEA forces. Organizing such a retreat is no easy task. Dessources takes as
				many refugees as possible aboard the Dreamer. Ysa wants to help the rebels fight. The
				characters should be involved in the fighting or evacuation effort somehow. After all,
				it was their presence that provided the catalyst that started the rebellion.

				* Escape - Her holds crammed with refugees and UAE ships starting to move in, Aglaee
				orders the characters back to the ship. Greatful for their help, Li lets them go. He
				sends Catherine Glit with them at the last minute, against her wishes. As the characters
				head for the spaceport, the rebels begin another counter-attack, slowly forcing the UAE
				ground troops back and taking the spaceport and ground-to-orbit weapons. The citizens
				who couldnt be evacuated riot, pelting helpless UEA infantry and marines with rocks and
				bricks. Things are obviously not going well for the UEA troops.

				* Copernicus Dome Disaster - Ansevik realizes that the rebels could use the city's
				ground-to-orbit weapons to attack his warships. He must now choose whether to withdraw
				or fire on the defensive batteries. In a panic, Ansevik orders his ships to attack the
				laser and missile batteries. The resulting explosions are far larger than expected and
				shatter the dome. A hasty retreat ensues as the Dome opens to vacuum, killing rebel,
				civilian, and UEA marine alike.

				* Chaos -  Ismael Li operates the Laser Lifter to boost the refugee ships away, including
				the Dreamer. Li's last words, relayed to his friends and helpers aboard the Dreamer, are
				My life for freedom! The Dreamer attempts to escape with the other refugee ships, but
				the UEA ships are positioned to easily stop them. The UEA demands their surrender, but
				the UEA ships are then ordered to focus on rescue instead of pursuing the refugee ships.

				* Aftermath - In the end, thousands are killed in Copernicus Dome. The UEA, of course,
				refuses to take the blame for the Dome disaster. Their first desperate response is to
				put the blame on the Jovian terrorists who abducted Peyarje. Reporters use Anseviks
				actions as fodder for their own counter-attack against UEAs propaganda.

				* Notes - Develop the rebellion and the rebels, especially Ismael Li. Emphasize the
				moons restrained and industrious culture and the rampant poverty and utilitarian
				nature of the underground cities. If appropriate, show the corruption of the UEA
				officials that oversee the colonies. Play up the initial hope and final despair of the
				rebels, the desperation of the refugees to find a better life, and the chaos of
				close-quarters fighting in the Lunar warrens.
			</summary>
		</scenario>
		<scenario name="Dreams of War">
			<summary>
				* Mission to Mars - The UEA is in pursuit again and logically expects the Dreamer to
				head to Jupiter. However, with its high speed escape and her holds crammed with refugees,
				theres no way for the Beautiful Dreamer to make Jupiter without running out of supplies
				or fuel. Fortunately for her crew and desperate passengers, the ship can easily make
				Mars. There, Aglaee DesSources hopes that the Martian Republic will be able to provide
				homes to the refugees.

				* Decoy - The UEA pursuit will soon catch up and they cannot be allowed to follow the
				Dreamer to Mars, so a desperate plan is devised. The booster rockets from the Moon are
				removed and fitted with decoy gear to make the rockets appear as the Dreamer. The pilots
				will escort the rockets on the current course while the Dreamer makes a course
				correction and silently coasts towards Mars. The escort will engage enemy mechs drawing
				out the enemies resources while maintaining the charade as long as possible. Once the
				decoy is discovered the pilots must return to the rockets and activate the massive
				rockets to boost away at high speed to rendevous with the Dreamer. This plan is loaded
				with risk and the pilots will probably be caught or killed. Their farewell is long and
				emotional. After the Moon, the pursuit fleet commander has been ordered to kill everyone
				aboard the Dreamer both in revenge and to eliminate witnesses. When the UEA pursuit
				fleet catches up to the decoy, a heated fight begins with no quarter given. Because the
				UEA is out for blood, they focus on the pilots instead of the 'Dreamer'. The pilots are
				driven back and the ruse is discovered. The pilots must make a desperate dash to the
				booster and escape before they are blown out of the sky. Fortunately, they escape though
				with heavy losses and damage and rendevous with the Dreamer on schedule. The UEA fleet
				has overcommitted to Jupiter and are unable to pursue to Mars. Anxious days pass as the
				Dreamer travels at full speed to Mars. When they arrive they will have to hope that the
				Martian government doesn't arrest them on the spot. Meanwhile, Garand has deduced that
				the refugees will divert the Dreamer to Mars (because that's what he would do), but his
				disgust with his superiors' handling of the battle on the Moon causes him to go to Mars
				on his own.

				* Mars Arrival - The Dreamer enters Mars orbit and is immediately escorted by a fighter
				wing and two destroyers. The escort demands that the Dreamer stand down all weapons and
				prepare to be boarded. They have little choice in the matter. There is nowhere else to
				go. The boarding party secures the engine room and bridge and dock the Dreamer at the
				massive Orbital Elevator space station called Heaven. All passengers are taken to
				immigration while their ship is searched. Here they meet Yanna Summers, the chief
				adminstrator of the Elevator. Little information is forthcoming and all senior staff are
				to be taken by shuttle to Mars Federation police headquarters. As they descend, they get
				an amazing view of the incredible Orbital Elevator in action.

				* Stairway to Heaven - Constructed with the aid of Venus Bank, the Martian Orbital
				Elevator, Stairway to Heaven is a marvel of engineering. It stretches upwards from its
				base at Hell Station just north of the Federation capital of Kurtzenheim to the Heaven
				Station counterweight. The elevator is dominates the landscape and has become a symbol
				of Mars Federation authority. It shines like a moon day or night, and it catches the
				first light of day every sunrise before the rest of Mars. Its ore containers crawl up
				and down the tether 24 hours a day. The current chief adminstrator, Yanna Summers, is
				extremely organized and professional and keeps very tight ship.

				* Martian Politics - Since its creation, the Orbital Elevator has become the center of
				Martian politics. Mars has two major political factions: the Mars Federation and the
				Free Republic of Mars. The Mars Federation is an authoritarian regime. It controls most
				of Mars and is loosely allied with the UEA. The Free Republic of Mars is smaller and is
				largely at odds with everything the Federation does. The Orbital Elevator has become the
				center of Martian debate because the Federation controls the Elevator and the huge
				profits it produces will allow the Federation to dominate the Free Republic in just a
				few years. Open conflict on Mars has become common and numerous terrorist organizations
				perform increasingly savage raids on the Mars Federation. The Federation in turn blames
				the Republic of backing the terrorists which is not entirely without merit.

				* Life on Mars - At police headquarters, they must negotiate for asylum for the
				refugees and avoid arrest and extridition to the UEA. They meet with Paul Treben of the
				Solar Police who is surprised to learn of the unofficial version of the events on the
				Moon. He will report everything he learns to his superiors who will in turn secretly
				inform the UEA. Representatives from both political factions arrive intending to use the
				characters to their own ends. The Mars Federation wants to extridite the characters as
				terrorists, but the Free Republic grants the refugees asylum and puts a hold on the
				extridition of the crew of the Dreamer.

				* Waiting Around - Support for the UEA is weak here, so the characters are released for
				the time being, though they are escorted by an armed detail at all times. Garand and his
				elite unit are also poking around and soon confronts the high profile characters, but he
				has no authority on Mars and can do nothing while the characters remain. In the meantime,
				the refugees are brought to the Free Republic and a media circus begins as their stories
				hit the airwaves. The public is shocked and sympathetic to the Selenites, but this soon
				turns to rage as it becomes clear that the same thing could happen to them. The normal
				protests for fair use of the Orbital Elevator break out into massive riots and terrorist
				activity spikes across Mars.

				* Dangerous Liason - Though the govenments seems to treat the characters like criminals,
				the public treats them like celebrities or even heroes. While out and about, a pretty
				young woman approaches one of the males and gushes about how wonderful he is and leaves
				him her contact code on a slip of paper. After further inspection, the contact code is
				not a personal address but a secure web site. Following the link, they speak with the
				girl, Lydia Ketchum, but her manner is very different. She is a political radical who
				has been implicated in terrorist activity including attacks on police and bombings. She
				is proud of her actions and believes that giving her life for a free Mars would be a
				fair trade. She proposes a daring escape plan. Her people will help smuggle the
				characters up the elevator in a depressurize ore car. There they must fight their way
				through the station, take over the administration headquarters, and release their ship
				and mechs from impound. Her people can then use the station defenses to cover their
				escape. With the station under her control, she can negotiate fair use of the elevator
				going forward from a position of strength.

				* Departure - Lydia's plan does not sound entirely rational, and she is not the sort of
				person who can be trusted. However, without allies the characters are never going to
				escape Mars, so they have no choice but to take a chance regardless of the consequences.
				Catherine and Ibrahim are unsure of their long-term safety on Mars and decide to join
				the group to continue all the way to Jupiter despite the risks.

				* Hell Ride - After days of planning, Lydia's people distract the guards and the
				characters make a run for it. After they make their escape, they are swiftly taken to
				an ore processing plant and smuggled aboard an ore train car. In the train are guns,
				pressure suits, Lydia, and four of her people. The train goes to Hell station where the
				cars are searched. Tense moments pass as they wait for the inspector to get to their
				car. When he opens the car, he looks right at them, winks at Lydia, waves his scanner,
				and lets the car pass. The characters must take care not to be crushed when the train
				contents are dumped into an elevator crawler. Soon, the crawler begins its long, slow
				trip up the elevator.

				* Heaven Sent - When the elevator arrives at Heaven, its contents are dumped into an
				open bin. More of Lydia's sympathizers help them bypass security forces. Now the
				characters need to get to Heaven's Command Center with as little bloodshed as possible.
				Complicating the situation, Garand appears on a screen. He and his men have commendeered
				an elevator crawler and are on their way up with their mechs. Though Heaven is a huge
				structure, it is not a military installation, so with the help of sympathizers, getting
				to the Command Center is surprisingly easy. Yanna is enraged, but her actions are always
				pragmatic, so she surrenders the Command Center when the odds are stacked against her.

				* Elevator Falls - Once Command is secured, the way to the Dreamer is open. Lydia says
				she will cover their escape and then begin negotiations with the govenment for release
				of the station. She is, of course, lying. After the Dreamer departs, she does help the
				Dreamer escape by threatening the UEA ships who cannot fire on the station, but once the
				Dreamer is clear, she turns Heaven's weapons on the tether. As the support is destroyed,
				Heaven begins spinning out of orbit while the elevator cable begins to fall, slowly at
				first, then faster and faster. Garand uses his mech to punch free of the doomed elevator,
				but he is a very low orbit. The damage from the cable's impact is incredible, as the
				white-hot dimond-fiber cable slams into the red dust at several times the speed of sound.
				The elevator is more than one and a half the length of the planet's equator and slowly
				wraps itself around Mars destroying everything around it for miles. The impact raises a
				massive cloud of dust and leaves a huge canyon visible from space. The destruction is
				unequalled in the history of mankind. The death toll is in the millions. The UEA must
				rescue Garand and Heaven station, so the Dreamer crew can begin the sad trip to Jupiter.
			</summary>
		</scenario>
		<scenario name="Dreams of Death">
			<summary>
				* Epilogue - The Heaven crew is rescued from a harrowing tumble into space, but the
				station spins off into space. Lydia proudly takes full credit for the assault in the
				name of a free Mars. There is little doubt that Lydia will be tried and executed which
				seemed to be her plan from the start. Her testimony makes it seem that she duped the
				Dreamer crew into fighting her battle for her. There are many, however, who draw a
				connection between the Dreamer crew and the disasters on the Moon and Mars. They are
				not officially terrorists, but you wouldn't know it from some of the news stations. The
				elevator disaster almost exclusively harmed the Mars Federation which shifted the
				balance of power back toward the Free Republic, which was Lydia's intention. Garand was
				saved by a daring low-orbit rescue. The UEA uses his story and the elevator fall to try
				to deflect attention from their crimes on the Moon, but the UN determines that the
				Copernicus Disaster was an act of state oppression and that the UEA should be subjected
				to sactions.

				* Jupiter - With fresh supplies and full fuel tanks, the Dreamer is easily able to make
				Jupiter. There, Dr. Peyarje transfers to the JAW Skunk Works team on Joshua Station.
				His new thought control system is refitted into the new Prometheus prototype mech.

				* A Mad Plan - The UEA leadership assesses their situation are are not happy at all.
				They invested massive resources developing Dr. Peyarje's mech control system to gain the
				upper hand, but now that technology will shift military power toward the Jovians instead.
				Their actions have caused the Selenites to openly hate and fear them. The Martian
				economy is in ruins with their ally the Mars Federation hit hardest. The Venusian Bank
				is still behind them, but they won't be if UEA influence collapses. The military proposes
				a heartless plan: destroy the Jovian colonies now before the new technology can be used
				and the entire Solar System will fall under UEA control. The Venusians can be bought off.
				The disasters on the Moon and Mars leave them in no position to fight back. The other
				colonies are too small and will have to fall in line. All of this chaos has created an
				opportunity to establish a new order, but the time to act is now.

				* The Hammer Falls - The 4th Fleet, still assigned to recover Peyarje and waiting just
				outside of Jovian space, is ordered into action. The Elysee Station sensor net has been
				disabled by a UEA agent, allowing the fleet to close with the colony undetected. A
				powerful jamming device has been deployed by the fleet to prevent the station from
				calling for help. The ships and mechs are ordered to attack Joshua Station to disable
				their defenses and force them to negotiate the extradition of the 'terrorists'.
				Unknown to them, their attack is a diversion for an elite squad of marines in exo-suits
				who will use retro-rocket packs to deorbit Elysee Station. Their real plan is to send
				the capital colony and all its inhabitants plunging into the Jovian atmosphere within
				twenty-four hours. With its leaders and their central hub gone, the Jovians will fall
				under UEA control.

				* Dragonstriker - On Joshua station, the characters are introduced to the new elite
				Vindicator mechs as well as the prototype Prometheus. Each have been fitted with the new
				CAT control system, but have yet to be tested. Suddenly advanced warning alarms sound,
				the station is under attack! Ranho Garand's team of elite mechs are charging toward the
				station, his massive Dragonstriker armor slicing through the Jovian defenses. His
				intense will and discipline give him near-perfect control over the still imperfect
				control system fitted to the prototype Dragonstriker. The characters launch to meet him,
				and the Dreamer hastily launches to lend support to the defending destroyers. All long
				range communications are disrupted by jammers, so a courier ship is sent to warn the
				other colonies. The battle is intense, but before it can be resolved, the courier
				returns. The pilot, Carl DeMers, broadcasts a warning when the interference clears:
				there is another larger force that has attacked Elysee station! They have fixed rocket
				packs to the hull and are decelerating the entire colony out of orbit! Everyone at
				Elysee will die when the station breaks up in Jupiter's atmosphere.

				* Taking Sides - Klebs total lack of honor have pushed Garands loyalties to the
				breaking point. If he finds out about the true plan for Elysee, he will turn on Klebs
				fleet. This will cause other fleet elements loyal to Garand to turn or withdraw from
				combat. The mechs board their ships are are quickly, re-outfitted on the short trip to
				Elysee.

				* The God and the Dragon - They arrive at Elysee to find the battle in full swing, with
				the Jovian forces slowly being driven back by the UEA Fleet, and the retro-rockets are
				just beginning to fire. The JSS Godsfire, its weapon block mauled by enemy fire, is
				trying to evacuate as many civillians as it can, using its remaining firepower to keep
				the UEA exos and fighters at a distance. Two teams are deployed: one to fight the UEA
				special forces and disable the rockets, and the another to battle the UEA fleet. The
				arrival of the Prometheus and Dragonstriker, and a detachment of other exo-armors,
				quickly turns the tide of battle. The battle seems unlikely to be resolved soon, thanks
				to the power of Klebs Posideon flagship. Garand confronts his former boss, and flies
				straight toward the Posideon. The Dragonstriker is heavily damaged by the fire, but
				manages to clamp unto the Posideon's bridge and opens fire at point blank range. The
				Dragonstriker and Posideon go up in a massive explosion, damaging nearby ships. The tide
				of battle suddenly turns. Many UEA soldiers were unhappy with Admiral Kleb's actions and
				are easy to convince with impassioned plees. The rockets are disabled and Elysee station
				uses its engines to regain its correct orbit.

				* Epilogue: Garand - Of Garand, no remains are found. While he could have escaped in the
				escape pod, it seems unlikely that he survived. That the CSS Karana, an Uller-class
				missile cruiser believed destroyed during the battle, is missing is noticed during
				cleanup months later, but no connection is ever made between the two events. Garand did
				survive, but was horribly wounded, and was recovered later by the crew of the Karana,
				who had trained under him.

				* Epilogue: UEA - Kleb was killed in the destruction of the Scyllas bridge. The UEA
				government publically him off as a 'lone gunman' who acted without official sanction and
				engages in a ruthless purge of the Navys command structure to 'remove any who might
				seek to follow Admiral Klebs example'. In fact, they use this to eliminate to expunge
				or marginalize those taught by Garand or 'corrupted' by his philosophy from the upper
				ranks. Their shadowy ties to Venus remain as strong as ever, and, much to their relief,
				the diplomatic repercussions of the Odyssey affair fade away over the next year.

				* Epilogue: Venus - Malachai falls into disgrace with VenusBank for his failure to
				produce results or protect the existance of Project Methuselah, and becomes a
				dissatisfied freelancer. For the next decade he wanders the solar system, hatching mad
				schemes to put him in the good graces of his former employer once more and destroy the
				Confederation. He is eventually captured by SolaPol and disappears. VenusBank begins
				scaling back its operations slightly, uncertain of just how much the Confederation knows.
				No public or private charges are ever made by the Confederation over the poaching of the
				Floaters or the aims of Project Methuselah, leaving the Bank executives in a very
				unpleasant information vacuum.

				* Epilogue: Mars - The consequences of the Martian Elevator take a long time to
				show themselves. Initially, neither Martian government accuses the other of the
				collapse. Evidence is sketchy, and the presence of Jovian and UEA agents on-site makes
				things even more uneasy.
			</summary>
		</scenario>
	</section>
	<section name="Europa Incident">
		<summary>
			* The Flashlight Project - Blocked from what they believed to be their rightful control
			over the colonies at every turn by the Jovian Confederation, UEA launched several
			top-secret advanced weapons projects.  One of the less successful efforts was the
			Flashlight Project, an attempt to develop heavy autonomous drone combat spacecraft.  The
			two Lucifer prototypes, the ultimate end result of the project, were ideal for commerce
			raiding.  They could operate for years without more than cursory communication with their
			home base; their stealth systems could hide them from the most determined sensors; and
			their heavy array of particle beam weapons could savage a warship in a single volley.
			* The project turned out to be too complicated and expensive to mass-produce, but the
			prototype was dispatched to Jovian space for 'field trials', with orders to destroy any
			target with a Jovian registry it came across. The plan was to disrupt the Jovian economy
			enough to make them more pliable to UEA demands.
			* After the Battle of Elysee, the UEA council determined that the Lucifer would be a
			political hand grenade if it was captured. They ordered the Lucifer to self destruct, but
			it had already disappeared in the radiation and magnetic fields around Jupiter, the very
			fields they had relied upon to hide the drone as it went about its work.  Finally, the
			crew managed to get a signal through, but some interference caused the drone to change
			course and crash on Europa instead of self-destructing.
		</summary>
		<scenario name="A Damaged Freighter">
			<summary>
				* The UEA Black Eagle Squadron is smuggled aboard the freighter Narsus to recover the
				datacore of the Lucifer and destroy any evidence. The Black Eagles had planned to slip
				onto Europa undetected after the Narsus dropped into orbit around the moon. Supposedly,
				she was to be taking on water for a journey up to Ganymede. The plan was that she
				would deploy the Eagles exo-armors, head off to deliver the rest of her cargo, then
				return and pick them up a week later. Faulty parts led to an explosion in Narsus'
				engines during her insertion burn. The captain managed to drop the freighter into a
				stable orbit around Europa before the engines completely died, but then, as is
				standard practice for merchant crews, immediately set off a distress beacon.
				* With all the unexplained attacks in Jovian space lately, an exo-armor patrol is
				dispatched from their carrier to investigate. The crew seems to sincerely have
				severe engine trouble. Some of the Jovians will have to board the Narsus leaving
				their exos tethered to the hull. The remainder stay on patrol.
				* Inside, the freighter is in zero-g and is particularly cramped. The crew's story
				seems to hold up, but the four passengers are uneasy about the situation. The engines
				are in bad shape and are irradiated. The cargo hold has large, sealed, liquid cargo
				bins labeled with warnings as liquid methane. If the Jovians start attempt to open the
				cargo, the captain will lose his nerve and reveal that the passengers are UEA pilots.
				A firefight erupts and the Black Eagles get into the cargo containers and remotely
				open the cargo bay to vacuum. The UEA troops escape by detonating the Narsus as a
				distraction (killing the crew, of course) and releasing an ECM scrambler pod. They
				have clearly descended to Europa somewhere.
			</summary>
		</scenario>
		<scenario name="Escape to the Ice Planet">
			<summary>
				* With Europa's low surface gravity, the Black Eagle team's exo-armors descend to the
				surface safely using their own thrusters. Europas surface is covered by a thick layer
				of ice. Unlike ice on Earth, this isnt slippery - its nowhere near the freezing
				point. The surface is perilous with unstable ground and spontaneous geysers.
				* The UEA team radios for a pickup using a small signal booster in orbit. They then
				begin a tedious search for the Lucifer.
				* The JAF patrol rejoins its carrier and begins a search of Europa.
				* The UEA team eventually discovers the crashed Lucifer but finds footprints and
				vehicle tracks nearby. The data core has already been removed and taken to the small
				research station Europa 1. The UEA team breaks the ice beneath the Lucifer to let it
				fall into the ocean below never to be discovered. Then they must follow the tracks to
				recover the data core before its secrets are revealed and/or silence the witnesses.
				* When the JAF arrives, they must deduce what has happened and race to intercept the
				UEA team.
			</summary>
		</scenario>
		<scenario name="Hide and Seek">
			<summary>
				* Europa 1 is not well guarded, but it is a large facility with lots of staff. The
				UEA must infiltrate the base and quickly locate the data core before the rendezvous in
				12 hours. The station is unarmed, and if a firefight erupts, everyone will flee to the
				underground shelters. If they run out of time, the UEA may be forced to destroy the
				base, but this would not guarantee the destruction of the data core.
				* The JAF can immediately land at the base and are introduced to Dr. Han Krieger and
				his attractive daughter Paula. They have recovered the data core, but did not have
				sufficient equipment to study the downed ship.
				* If the UEA can get close enough they can hack the core remotely and trigger a data
				wipe. They may also threaten to blow up the base if they are not given the core.
				Whether they succeed or not, the UEA will have to retreat back to the rendezvous
				point or be stranded. When they retreat, the JAF will have to guess at where they are
				going and why, but either way they will need to pursue them.
			</summary>
		</scenario>
		<scenario name="Hell Unchained">
			<summary>
				* Suddenly, a large shadow passes overhead. It's a frigate, the UEA pickup has arrived.
				Six exo-armors exit its bay and begin to advance.
				* As the JAF prepare to meet them, the frigate opens fire. Suddenly, there is a deep
				tremor in the ice below. The UEA agents feel it too and stop code. Suddenly, from under
				the ice, an impossibly brilliant beam of light lances up to engulf one of the
				descending exo-armors. It doesn't explode but it just melts and disappears in the beam.
				Soon, the ice seems to explode and the enormous black form of the Lucifer rises from
				below.
				* With its data core removed and a firefight nearby, it switched to its limited,
				secondary systems and it is unable to determine friend from foe. Its massive guns are
				clearly building another charge and moments later it fires at the frigate's engines.
				The crippled engines briefly leak fusing hydrogen before destroying the frigate in a
				nuclear fireball. It then begins to engage the new exo-armors from the frigate.
				* The JAF and UEA will have to quickly come to terms with the fact that the Lucifer
				will kill them all unless they work together.
				* If the Lucifer escapes, it will boosts off Europa into a tight slingshot orbit
				and then use its ECM systems to hide in Jupiters radiation belt. Without its higher
				brain functions, the Lucifer is more of a killing machine than an assassin, so it is
				now a question of how much damage it will do before it is taken down.
				* If the Lucifer is destroyed over Europa, it will crash into the ice and be lost in
				the depths. Without their pickup, the UEA agents will have to negotiate the terms of
				their surrender. Regardless, they will be tried and interrogated for their actions.
			</summary>
		</scenario>
	</section>
	<section name="Jovian History">
		<summary>
			* Mercury, Helios Station - A permanent colony of 8 million orbiting Mercury is
			established. Its orbit puts it constantly in Mercury's shadow protecting it from
			most of the Sun's deadyly rays. Naturally, it has access to almost limitless
			solar power. All equipment around Mercury is outfitted with a unique heavy armor
			that combines hard radiation shielding with solar collection.

			* Venus, New Tokyo - The capital of Venus is a sprawling megaplex of 15 million at
			the North Pole of Venus. Though terraforming has been going on for decades, the
			poles are still the only places where the temperatures are survivable. The city
			is completely enclosed and partially underground. Industry is relegated to the
			wastelands outside. The Venusian bank invested heavily in developing Venus and has
			seen phenomenal growth. The bank now effectively owns the entire planet.

			* Earth 2210 - The UAE launches an attack against the Jovian civilian colonies in an
			attempt to push the colonies back into line.
			* Mars, Marsquake - The obital elevator around Mars is destroyed by sabotage, and
			the enormous, carbon-diamond fiber cable was slowly dragged from orbit as the
			planet turned. The cable dropped with devastating force, wrapping around the
			equator two and a half times. Fortunately, the sparse population of Mars reduced
			the scope of the devastation. There is a common joke that Mars is now the only
			planet with an actual black line at the equator. Hot heads and smugglers have
			take to racing down the trench created by the cable.

			* War Aftermath - Some UAE leaders were found guilty of crimes against humanity
			for their attacks against the Jovian colonies. The other colonies increasingly see
			Earth as irrelevant to their future. Earth politics is divided on how to proceed.
			The UAE has gone underground and now covertly funds a paramilitary group of
			disgruntled combat veterans and pirates in order to further its aims in space.
		</summary>
	</section>
	<section name="Jovian Characters">
		<unit name="Aglaee Dessources">
			<summary>
				* Mysterious, beautiful, and cold, Aglaee DesSources is the captain of the
				Beautiful Dreamer, a privateer vessel. Once an extremely promising CEGA Navy
				captain, she retired at the age of thirty to her present position.
				* 42 year old aristocratic-looking woman.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Adrian Allen">
			<summary>
				* Adrian is bookish and quiet pilot unlike the adventurous, rowdy Exo-pilot crowd.
				He is inexperienced and sometimes panics in combat when clear solutions are not
				obvious. He is currently single athough he is attracted to Foxy Fujima.
				* Age: 22
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Madelaine Koudriopoulos">
			<summary>
				* Strong willed and tenacious fighter pilot.
				* She is the only daughter of Konrad Koudroipoulos, Khannan's commander. Because of
				this, she had to fight with pilots who accused her of favoritism and her father who
				made every effort to get her to step down.
				* She has been teamed up with Adrian Allen who has become like a big brother to her.
				She interferes a lot with his personal life, much to his despair. She is bold but
				is uncomfortable dating, so she currently has no boyfriend.
				* Age: 21
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Foxy Fujima">
			<summary>
				* Freelance reporter travelling from cylinder to cylinder in search of a story. She
				has a high attitude of the moral importance of reporting, so she will not cover
				trival stories which has limited her career development. Her beauty has attracted many
				men, but she seems to only be interested in her career.
				* Age: 22
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Dr. Agram Peyarje">
			<summary>
				Brilliant scientist researching human/machine interfaces.
				A staunch pacifist, Peyarje is repelled by war in general and utterly
				disgusted by what CEGA plans to do with his inventions. He sees the Confederation as his best
				hope of escape, even if they too are warmongers.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Dr. Catherine Glit">
			<summary>
				* Catherine used to serve as Ismael Li's personal assistant and moderator. She
				is now the representative of the escaping Lunar refugees.
				* She is an excellent doctor, highly regarded by all. While she appears cold
				to everyone, she is shy and only opens up to close friends.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Ismael Li">
			<summary>
Ismael Li is the leader and driving force behind the burgeoning Lunar resistance movement. Once
a miner, Li worked hard, long hours in the tunnels deep below the Lunar surface and Helium-3
harvesters. He quit in disgust when he realized that the company hed worked ten hard years for
was constantly operating at a loss and systematically abusing its employees in order to provide
CEGA and massive Earth corporations with cheap Lunar ores. Using the excellent education
provided to all Selenties, Li spoke out against the CEGA occupation, making speeches and
distributing eloquent pleas for regime change in an attempt to awaken the populace to the truth
of their situation.

Five years ago, under investigation by CEGA and Lunar police forces, Li took his crusade
underground. No matter what he did, legitimate means would only get him arrested. He set
about building a proper revolutionary organization out of the public eye, aiming to drive CEGA off
the Lunar surface by force of arms. Strangely, this has won him many more converts among the
usually peaceful Selenites than his speaches ever did. He finds this somewhat disheartening,
but still forges ahead.

Li is now ready to launch his uprising. The arrival of the PCs has moved his timetable up a bit,
as their actions on Venus have distracted many of CEGAs forces and their skills can be a great
help to him. He is a fundamentally honest man, and will promise fuel, parts, and provisions
in exchange for the PCs help. He will give them what he promised without short-changing or
holding back. He also truly believes in his cause, and would willing sacrifice his life to save any
of his supporters.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Jovian Floater">
			<summary>
				* The Jovian floater is giant, blimp-sized animal filled with gas that lives its entire
				life floating in Jupiter's atmosphere. It has a unique biology similar to photosynthesis
				that consumes water, methane, and radiation to produce food. This biology also produces
				a short-lived compound that repairs radiation damage to its DNA which allows it to
				survive in the harsh radioactive environment. The medical significance of this creature
				especially to space flight cannot be overstated. How life could begin in such high
				radioactivity remains a mystery.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Luka Ansevik">
			<summary>
Captain Luka Ansevik is the commander of the small CEGA lunar garrison force. Captain
Ansevik is throughly unimaginative, a very by-the-book officer, assigned to a post not likely to tax
her capabilities. After all, what threat could the unarmed and industrious Selenites pose to the
military might of CEGA? When revolution erupts around her, Ansevik will do her best to contain
it, but becomes increasing desperate as the situation unravels. She knows that failure to resolve
the situation before her superiors are forced to take notice will be the end of her career.
Ansevik is an officer focused on tactics and administrative work. As such, her combat skills
are virtually nonexistent - she is much more comfortable ordering others into combat than
fighting herself. This leads to disaster, as it leaves Ansevik out of touch with her troops as
they desperately fight the rebels in the streets of Copernicus. Finally, increasingly desperate to
contain the situation, she could be the one to order the dome blown.
(Ind) Ysa Cantroni
Ysa will be in her element during the Lunar uprising. Action, crusading for justice, and a bevy of
human interest stories to practice her reporting skills on! Having spent a year touring the Earth
system at one point, Ysa has a number of useful contacts on Luna that can supplement those
provided by DesSources and Li. Even if she doesnt travel down from the Dreamer with the PCs
initially, she will try to find some way down so she can help the Selenites of Copernicus fight for
their freedom once the uprising begins.
Of course, Ysa might not be quite as good at tunnel fighting as she thinks she is. Saving her
from herself could be an exciting and frustrating subplot for a PC, especially one who has
become emotionally involved with her. Having a mysterious masked figure in a red CEGA exosuit
(Garand, of course) help save her and keep her safe from CEGA forces, but carefully avoid
aiding the rebels, might create an interesting mystery... Or not, depending on how sharp your
players are.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Lydia Ketchum">
			<summary>
				* Lydia Ketchum is a Martian Republic Rook, a Ranger trained for deep-cover operations
				within the Federation. One of the Republics best rangers, shes been assigned to watch
				the orbital elevator. She takes her job quite seriously, and has so far managed to avoid
				drawing the notice of the Federation.

				* Unfortunately, not all is as it appears with Ranger Ketchum. She is from the Isidis
				Planitia, an isolated area that recently (2207) declared its independence from the rest
				of the Republic. The Isidisians are even more militant about the Federation than
				ordinary Republic citizens, and see the Federations orbital elevator as a very personal
				and insufferable insult to their national pride.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Yanna Summers">
			<summary>
Yanna Summers is the decidated and hardworking administrator of the Martian Orbital Elevator.
While her actual domain is very small - she only has direct control over Heaven and Hell station -
the amount of commerce that travels up and down the beanstalk has given her a sizable amount
of influence within the Federations government. This is counterbalanced by her attempts to open
Federation society up a little. Her position and efforts, however, did draw the attention of the
Society of the Evolved Human, which she eagerly joined when offered membership.
Yannas connection to the Society was what lead Aglaee to steer the players towards her, and
inclined her to help them find a home for the refugees. It also could be what leads to her asking
the PCs for help with the scientist case - another test by the Society to help them reach their
potential. She has contacts all through the Federation bureaucracy, and could use them to help
the players with their investigation... But there will likely be a price of some kind, as shes already
stretched her resources thin to secure passage for the refugees. This could, however, lead to the
Refugees Under Attack subplot. Or Yanna could be a background character that just serves to
lead the PCs into the episode.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Ysa Cantroini">
			<summary>
Ysa
has spent the past several years travelling the solar system and working odd job. This has given
her an extremely wide range of skills (though none at more than 2/1 or 2/2) and connections,
especially here on her native Venus.
Ysa is bright and intelligent, generally assuming a quiet but cheerful air. Shes a wandering soul,
and doesnt think she could ever stay happy in one place or one job for the rest of her life. She
is seriously considering becoming a reporter, however, as this gives her a way to travel and
encounter a wide variety of experiences while getting paid and doing good. Much to her shame,
her father is a high-ranking executive in the Venusian bank. She has cut all ties with him, and
does not regret doing so, but this secret connection could still draw suspicion to her.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Admiral Russel Kleb">
			<summary>
Admiral Kleb is the throughly corrupt commander of the CEGA 4th Fleet. A hard-line war
supporter, Kleb believes the inhabitants of the colonies to be completely inferior to native
Terrans. This provides him with the justification he needs to take any action in pursuit of CEGA
dominance. He is in the pay (and service) of the Venusian bank, as they provide him with the
means to further his own ambitions, but he will not hesitate to betray them for his own advantage.
They are, after all, just inferior colonists, cowardly employing bribery when they should be using
righteous force.

					* Despite his biases, Kleb is a brilliant tactician, equally adept at combat
					maneuvers and political backstabbing. He is a staunch member of the UEA ruling
					faction, and an adherent to the warship-centric old school of military thinking. To
					him, adherents of the exo-centric school are children playing with fancy new toys.
					Ranho Garand, as the most prominently successful exopilot in the UEA navy and focus
					of the Dragonstriker program, is a frequent target of Klebs scorn.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Ranho Garand">
			<summary>
				* Commander of the 3rd Division of the CEGA 4th fleet, Garand is an ace exo-armor pilot
				and media darling. Despite his military connections, Garand is a devoted member of
				Changs political faction. While he does believe the military to be a necessary tool, he
				doesnt believe that it is the proper one to further UEAs domination over their wayward
				colonies. He was one of UEAs first exo-armor pilots, and taught many of the current
				generation, passing on both his piloting skills and his philosophy.

				Garand is a man of honor and discipline, with a spotless service record and excellent
				reputation. He does not enjoy killing or combat, but his honor demands that he follow
				orders and defend his people. Despite his iron will, he is prone to fits of irrational
				rage towards those who have forced him to commit (or involved him in) dishonorable acts.
			</summary>
		</unit>
	</section>
	<section name="Commercial Spacecraft">
		<unit name="Albatross Transorbital Shuttle" mass="45tons" speedair="1200kph" speedspace="1.5g">
			<summary>
				* The Albatross is the latest in a long line of shuttles used for cargo and
				passenger transfers to various atmospheres. One or two are standard equipment for
				any large military ship.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Beautiful Dreamer Transport" mass="10000tons" length="270m" crew="54">
			<summary>
				* The Beautiful Dreamer, at first sight, seems to be a standard Inari-class liner. As
				with many Inari, the Dreamer has been modified heavily, and there are many differences
				in the ships lines. Two concealed railguns run along the ships spine, providing an
				unpleasant and unexpected punch. The cargo bays on the crafts edges have been modified
				to carry mechs and fighters, complete with concealed catapults.
				* 2 Medium Railguns
				* 4 Mech Bays - Cannot land fighters.
				* 2 Magnetic Catapults
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Inari Space Liner" mass="10000tons" length="200m" crew="108">
			<titles>Georgia on my Mind</titles>
			<summary>
				* Unlike the bulk transport Mule, the Inari was designed to be a high speed passenger
				liner to get people quickly between the planets. Though not as modular as the Mule,
				the Inari can be heavily customized to specific tasks. Though it is not a military
				vessel, the Inari is fast and can be modified to be cary significant armor and weapons,
				thus making it well suited as a privateer.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Carver Mining Ship" length="80m" width="80m" mass="1200tons" speed=".15g">
			<summary>
				* The Carver is designed for the purpose seeking out and mining asteroids.
				The ship is very odd looking with three insect-like legs surrounding the
				main laser drill. The standard protocol for asteroid mining is to land on
				a mineral-rich feature, drill a deep tunnel, and then pressurize the
				tunnel so further operations can be done without environment suits. Ore
				is sent on a conveyor belt to the onboard smelter for separation and
				purification.
				* The Carver is intended to work perpetually. Its drive system is slow
				but extremely robust, able to use mined hydrogen for fuel and any waste
				material as reaction mass. Small tugs commute back and forth carrying ore
				to nearby space colonies and returning with supplies and spare parts. The
				tugs also carry replacement crew members.
				* The Carver has been in service for so long that their prices have come
				down dramatically. Since this work is enormously profitable, banks are
				willing to finance individuals if they can demonstrate a sound business
				plan.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Mule Freighter" length="345m" width="40m" mass="4000tons" speed=".4g" crew="6">
			<titles>Narsus</titles>
			<summary>
				* The Mule Freighter is a simple, reliable design for transporting large
				amounts of cargo across the solar system. It has no interior cargo hold,
				instead it has a series of connectors to link self contained cargo pods
				of various sizes. The connectors can also be used to hook onto asteroids
				or other ships to allow the Mule to act as a tug.
				* The Mule is the most common ship in the solar system and is used by
				every government and commercial space organization. Because the Mule is
				so versatile, it can even be used as a slow carrier or missile gunboat.
				For similar reasons, it is a favorite ship for smuggling or piracy as
				well.
				* Its acceleration reduces as its load increases. It can transport up to
				40ktons before its acceleration becomes too low to be practical.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Ox Orbital Tug" mass="41tons" speed=".5g">
			<summary>
				* The Ox is a space-only shuttle used for short tranports between space
				stations, tugbot duty, asteroid transport, and salvage operations. It has
				large manipulator arms to manage unusually shaped loads. It is a very
				sturdy if slow craft.
			</summary>
		</unit>
	</section>
	<section name="Jovian Federation">
		<summary>
			* Jovian capital ships are built for easy maintainance and reuse.  They are composed of 4
			sections: engine, cargo, habitat, and mission. All but the mission section can be
			interchanged with the equivalent sections from other ships. The habitat ring can even be
			removed for short range missions, or additional cargo modules can be added for greater
			endurance.
		</summary>
		<unit name="Jovian Pilot" />
		<unit name="Jovian Mech Jock" />
		<unit name="Jovian Tech" />
		<unit name="Lancer Space Interceptor" height="25m" width="10m" mass="50tons" speedspace="3.2g">
			<summary>
				* Despite the heavy investment in Mech Suits, Jovian interceptors remain
				an important part of Jovian armed forces. Their high acceleration allows
				them to be sent as the first line of defense ahead of the slower Mech
				Suits. They are well suited to recon and hit-and-run missions. They carry
				variable weapon pods for specialized recon, ECM, bomber, or long-range
				scouting missions.
				* 1 Light Laser Cannon
				* 6 Light Missiles
				* 2 Medium Missiles
				* 1 Heavy Missile
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Pathfinder Mech Suit" height="15.4m" width="11m" mass="35tons" speedland="26kph" speedspace="2.8g" image="JovianChronicles/PathfinderToken.png">
			<summary>
				* The Pathfinder is a rugged, simple to maintain Exo Suit design that forms the majority
				of the Jovian Mech forces. It is very agile but relatively fragile and mounts only
				light weaponry because it is designed primarily as a scout craft. Its high speed,
				agility, and exceptional close combat abilities proved the value of Mech Suit design and
				it remains the most iconic Mech Suit in existence.
				* 1 Medium Particle Cannon
				* 2 Medium Missiles
				* 2 Plasma Lances
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Retaliator Mech Suit" height="15.5m" width="12m" mass="42tons" speedland="66kph" speedspace="2.4g">
			<summary>
				* The Retailator is the standard Jovian interceptor Mech. Well-armed and fast for its
				size, it can take on larger opponents and come out on top. Its speed comes at the
				sacrifice of some armor unfortunately and its thrusters always overheat forcing pilots
				to take great care or risk burned out thrusters.
				* 1 Medium Rail Cannon
				* 4 Medium Missiles
				* 6 Light Missiles
				* 2 Plasma Lances
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Vindicator Mech Suit" height="16m" width="14m" mass="70tons" speedland="36kph" speedspace="1.8g">
			<summary>
				* The Vindicator is the most powerful mass-produced Mech in the solar system. It carries
				massive armor and armament, but its high cost limits its use to a few elite pilots. It
				is also painfully slow compared to the Pathfinders and Retailators it flies with.
				* 1 Medium Rail Cannon
				* 1 Medium Laser Cannon
				* 10 Heavy Missiles
				* 3 Plasma Lances
				* 2 Anti Missile Systems
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Prometheus Mech Suit" height="18m" mass="64tons">
			<summary>
				* The Prometheus was intended to be a prototype for a new generation of mech suits which
				would be more efficient, better armed, and faster than their predecessors. However, as
				development progressed, several experimental systems were added that made it a one of a
				kind wonder that could never be mass produced.
				* 1 Heavy Plasma Cannon
				* 2 Light Plasma Cannons
				* 2 Plasma Lances
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Prometheus Storm Attacker" height="21m" mass="82tons">
			<summary>
				* The [Prometheus Mech Suit] can be equipped with a heavy set of extra armor and weapons.
				The additional mass of the armor is negated by additional thrusters. If these thrusters
				are damaged the armor can be jettisoned leaving a fully functional Promethus.
				* 1 Heavy Plasma Cannon
				* 2 Light Plasma Cannons
				* 2 Plasma Lances
				* 2 Heavy Laser Cannons
				* 1 Particle Scatter Gun
				* 80 Medium Missiles
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Athena Destroyer" length="291m" width="81m" mass="10ktons" speed=".8g">
			<summary>
				* Athena Destroyers function much as their wet navy ancestors. Depending
				on the political climate, they are either protective shepards or hunting
				wolves. The Athena's job is to get in the way of danger. If an unknown
				vessel is detected, the destroyer will move ahead into a blocking
				position to defend the rest of the fleet.
				* The Athena is particularly fast and maneuverable for a capital ship and
				works closely with any small craft.

				Weapons:
				* Point Defense System
				* 3x Particle Accelerators
				* 6x Railguns
				* 2x Area Defense Laser Cannon
				* 1x Missile Bay
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Forge Patrol Carrier" mass="39000tons" length="460m" width="285m">
			<summary>
				* Forge class carriers carry 12 pilots including squadron leaders.
				* There are 24 Forge class vessels commissioned.
				* Speed: .8g

				Weapons:
				* Point Defense System
				* 8 Rail Cannons
				* 2 Laser Cannons
				* 2 Missile Bays

				Vehicles:
				* 6x Mobile Suits with room for 12
				* 6x Catapults
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Explorer Scout Ship" length="345m" width="40m" mass="1ktons" speed=".4g">
			<summary>
				* One of the earliest planetary exploration ships, the Explorer has been
				produced for many years and is a reliable though uninspired design. Its
				modular design is its greatest asset and has ensured its continued use
				for decades. The crew module can be extended on a tether for artificial
				gravity with the other end counterbalanced by a water tank.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Gagarin Fleet Tender" mass="92ktons" length="740m" width="285m">
			<summary>
				* The Gagarin is a mobile tender designed to facilitate drydock style repairs close to the front lines.
				* Its mission hull is a gigantic workshop with huge door sections that can surround and refit a vessel in a
				pressurized environment.
				* Speed: .1g

				Weapons:
				* Point Defense System
				* 1x Missile Bay
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Javelin Cruiser" length="235m" width="72m" mass="20ktons" speed=".6g">
			<summary>
				* The Javelin is the most common warship in the Jovian Navy despite its
				age and lack of interceptor or Mech Bays. Its design is based on
				pre-Mech combat philosophy, emphasizing heavy weapons on capital ships as
				opposed to projection of force using smaller craft. Therefore, it is
				very heavily armed for a relatively small craft including the deadly
				heavy particle beam cannon.
				* Crew accomodations are small but comfortable with cleverly placed
				mirrors throughout the ship that give the illusion of greater interior
				space.
				* Point Defense System
				* 2 Heavy Rail Cannons
				* 1 Heavy Particle Beam Cannon Turret
				* 2 Missile Bay
				* 6 Space Dart Heavy Missiles
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Valiant Strike Carrier" length="320m" width="75m" mass="40ktons" speed=".8g">
			<summary>
				* The Valiant Strike Carrier is a ship like no other. Every other ship in
				the fleet is designed to work in cooperation with one another. The Valiant
				is designed to operate on long range, long term patrols with no backup.
				It is therefore heavily armed, armored, and carries extensive supplies
				and fabrication facilities.
				* It has two rotating crew decks that are very spacious for a spaceship.
				* 6 Heavy Rail Cannons on 2 Turrets
				* 1 Missile Bay
				* 1 Spinal Particle Beam Cannon
				* 6 Magnetic Catapults
				* 1 Certifuge Crew Module
				* 2 Lancer Interceptors
				* 2 Pathfinder Mech Suits
				* 2 Retaliator Mech Suits
				* 2 Vindicator Mech Suits
			</summary>
		</unit>
	</section>
	<section name="UEA">
		<titles>United Earth Alliance</titles>
		<unit name="UEA Commando" classification="Lt. Infantry">
		</unit>
		<unit name="UEA Marine" classification="Lt. Infantry">
			<summary>
				* Standard issue for all regular infantry and covert ops personnel.
				* High Impact Plastics with reinforced joints.
				* Enhanced Sensory gear and Comm System
				* HUD Targeting
				* Optional Backpacks with custom gear
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="UEA Mobile Infantry" classification="Hvy. Infantry">
			<summary>
				* Standard issue for assault and special forces personnel.
				* Hardened Crystalline Lattice Ceramic Compounds
				* Elaborate Sensory and Comm System
				* HUD Targeting with Smart Weapon links

				Powerful Backpack package including:
				* Ion thrusters
				* Heat Sink
				* Mini Fusion Plant
				* Y-rack gernade launcher (optional I-rack or micro turret)
				* Weapons can be powered from plant
				* Environmental Independence
				* Flamethrowers and Thrusters in arms and legs
				* Stealth options available
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="UEA Mobile Assault Infantry" classification="Hvy. Infantry">
			<summary>
				* Form is vaguely humanoid
				* Armor is extremely heavy and hardened
				* Weapons are built in and smart
				* Power Assist and Hand to Hand Weaponry make few obstacles a barrier

				Weapon Packages
				* When standing still the armor is considered a fixed weapon platform.
				* Heavy Machine Guns
				* Light Autocannon
				* Multiple Missile Launchers

				Backpack Package
				* Large Fusion Plant
				* Improved Heat Sink
				* Thrusters are extremely powerful
				* Wheels in legs for fast road movement
				* Speed and Maneuverability in open terrain are the trademarks of these types.
				* They are clumsy and overly destructive in tight quarters.
				* These models are purely Assault/Scorched Earth types similar to miniature tanks.
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="UEA Pilot" />
		<unit name="UEA Mecha Pilot" />
		<unit name="UEA Tech" />
		<unit name="Cerberus Mech Suit" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" height="17m" width="15m" mass="63tons" speedland="36kph" speedspace="1.8g">
			<summary>
				* The Cerberus is the first cutting edge Mobile Suit design from the UEA.
				* The name Cerberus comes from the large ECM pods on each shoulder which
				continually scan in all directions giving the appearance of 3 heads.
				* The Cerberus is designed as a hit-and-run unit, so it very fast and
				manueverable but has limited endurance by design. It is only available
				to commanders and elite pilots.
				* 30mm Massdriver with Depleted Uranium/Tungsten rounds. 20 shots.
				* Linked 20mm Vulcan Autocannons in the head.
				* 1 Plasma Lance
				* 1 Mech Combat Knife
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Dragonstriker Mech Armor" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="110tons" height="24m" image="JovianChronicles/DragonstrikerToken.png">
			<titles>CXE-01</titles>
			<summary>
				* Mechs are designed to battle other mechs and perhaps cripple enemy capital ships.
				The Dragonstriker is a unique prototype designed to attack enemy capital ships and
				installations directly. It is a massive mech, towering over other mechs and carrying
				formidable weapons to battle both capital ship and other mechs.
				* The Dragonstriker has a detachable booster that provides extra acceleration and range.
				The booster also houses the 2 Medium Laser cannons for strafing enemy capital ships.
				* 4 Heavy Anti-Ship Beam Cannon
				* 2 Medium Anti-Ship Laser Cannon (2 linked under for strafing attacks, mounted to booster)
				* 6 30mm Vulcan Autocannon (4 linked forward, 2 linked rear in head)
				* 4 Heavy Anti-Ship Missile (4 forward)
				* 2 Anti-Missile Laser Turret (1 forward, 1 rear)
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Hachiman Destroyer" classification="Hvy. Spacecraft" mass="5500tons" length="208m" width="80m" speed=".6g" crew="60">
			<summary>
				* The Hachiman is the workhorse of the UEA navy. They have been produced
				for many years with minor upgrades.
				* 1 Point Defense System
				* 6 Railcannon Turrets
				* 2 Missile Bays
				* 2 Laser Turrets
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Lucifer Cybersat" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="95tons" height="18.8m" speedspace="4g">
			<titles>CXS-01B, Automated Experimental Terror Raider</titles>
			<summary>
				* The Lucifers designed for one purpose - to ambush and kill enemy warships.  Its
				sophisticated Stealth systems allow it to hide and its strong electronic warfare suite
				prevents its prey from calling for help.  Powerful thrusters allow it to accelerate at
				incredible speeds, and a cluster of six small linked particle cannons and two large
				ones allow it to inflict massive damage very quickly.
				* Armor - Despite the advanced technology, its armor is quite thin for its size, and
				in a stand-up fight, it will almost certainly lose. The only questions are how to
				force it into a stand-up fight and how many of its attackers it can take with it.
				* Particle Cannons - The combined power of the dual particle cannons are equal to a
				spaceship's main gun. They have separate fusion engines just to recharge its capacitors,
				but it still takes 30 seconds between firings.
				* Particle Array - The 6 smaller particle cannons are designed for rapid fire against
				fast moving targets and are used between firing of the main guns.
				* Claws - Its claws are independent wire-guided drones armed with small energy weapons
				to deal with enemy interceptors. The claws are very fast and agile, but not very tough.
				They can replenish their fuel reserves by docking with the Lucifer.
				* Speed - The drones will almost never use their full top speed, and the Lucifer will
				make every effort to conserve its remass.  For long-range travel, it wont boost at
				more than 0.4 or 0.6 Gs except in short bursts.  Much of its time will be spent
				drifting along a medium-traffic orbit.
				* Stealth - The Lucifer carries an advanced ECM/stealth package that allows it to
				sneak up on enemies and attempt to cripple them while scrambling any distress calls.

				ECM(6, 10km), Stealth (6);
				Quantity	Name	Type	Arc	ACC	DM	BR	ROF	Perks + Flaws	Ammo
				1	Particle Cannon Cluster	E	F	+0	x12	4	+4	Hw,Red;AD(2),HEAT	Unl.
				2	Mega Particle Cannon	E	F	-1	x30	7	-1	Red,Hw;AD(2),HEAT;Link	Unl.
			</summary>
			<skill name="Mission Section">
				<specialty name="Stealth Vessel" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Lucifer Claw Drone" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="3tons" speedspace="5g">
			<summary>
				Armor:	10/20/30
				*Miscellaneous Threat Value (MTV): -
				Crew:	Computer 1 (Dumb, Level 2) (2 actions)

				Accessories: Autopilot; Arm: Manipulator Arm (R5, Can Punch); Armor: HEAT Resistant(5); Communications (-2, 2km);
				Hostile Environment Protection: Radiation (4), Vacuum, Extreme Cold; Sensors(+0, 2km); Vulnerable to Haywire;
				Quantity	Name	Type	Arc	ACC	DM	BR	ROF	Perks + Flaws	Ammo
				1	Laser Cannon	E	FF	+1	x10	5	+0	Red;AD(1),HEAT	Unl.
				1	Plasma Lance	E	F	+0	x15	M	+0	AC,Red;HEAT	Unl.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Siren Space Interceptor" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" length="14m" width="12m" mass="40tons" speedspace="3.5g">
			<summary>
				* The Siren Fighter is the standard medium range interceptor spaceship
				used by the UEA. It is faster than any other short range space craft in the
				Solar System, but without high mobility verniers it is outclassed by Mobile
				Suits. It is ideally suited for patrolling and policing the space lanes.
				* The Siren can be launched from Earth using a booster rocket making it even more
				practical for Earth defense.
				* 2 Medium Railguns
				* 6 Medium Missiles
				* 4 Light Missiles
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Syreen Mech Suit" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" height="17.2m" width="17.5m" mass="52tons" speedspace="3g" image="JovianChronicles/SyreenToken.png">
			<summary>
				* The Syreen Suit is a Siren space fighter retrofitted into a Mech Suit. It was hastily
				constructed when the first conflict with the Jovians displayed the dominant mobility of
				the Jovian Mech Suits.
				* As an efficient and cheap design, it can be fielded in large numbers. However, it does
				not compare well to the new Mech Suits that it is meant to face, so casualties are high.
				* The Syreen can be launched from Earth using a booster rocket making it even more
				practical for Earth defense.
				* 2 Heavy Missiles
				* 6 Medium Missiles
				* 4 Light Missiles
				* Point defense laser system
				* 2 Crude manipulator arms for close combat.
				* The command variant includes a powerful ECM pod.
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Poseidon Battlecruiser" classification="Hvy. Spacecraft" length="325m" width="200m" mass="30ktons" speedspace=".5g" crew="200">
			<summary>
				* The Poseidon Class Battlecruiser is the top of the line UEA warship. It
				gets its name from the two rotating living sections that give the ship the
				appearance of a trident.
				* The Poseidon outclasses any other warship from any faction and is a
				menancing presense. It was, however, designed before the advent of Mech
				Suits, so it carries more interceptors than Mechs.
				* Point Defense System
				* 4 Particle Accelerator Batteries
				* 4 Railcannon Batteries
				* 6 Interceptors
				* 4 Mech Suits
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Tengu Escort Carrier" classification="Hvy. Spacecraft" length="250m" width="38m" mass="25ktons" speedspace=".5g" crew="24">
			<summary>
				* The Tengu is a long range craft designed for limited engagements and
				policing. It has extensive supplies but lacks firepower.
				* 1 Point Defense System
				* 2 Missile Bays
				* 2 Mech Suits
				* 2 Fighters
				* 2 Catapults
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Wyvern Mech Suit" height="17m" length="4m" width="14m" mass="55tons" speed="1.4g" speedland="36kph" speedair="2.4mach" image="JovianChronicles/WyvernToken.png">
			<summary>
				* The Wyveern is the first and most numerous of the UEA Mech Suits.
				Though a copy of the Martial Federation Defender, it is a sturdy,
				reliable and most importantly mass-produceable design. Its primary
				limitation is the lack of energy weapons which limits its combat
				endurance before it needs to be rearmed.
				* 1 Hyperbazooka
				* 2 Massdriver Machineguns
				* 2 Self guided Missiles
			</summary>
		</unit>
	</section>
</chapter>
<chapter name="Mobile Suit Gundam Equipment">
	<section name="Gundam Equipment">
		<summary>
			* Energy rating for MW weapons assumes a 3 second burst.
		</summary>
		<item name="Titanium Composite">
			<summary>
				This is the state of the art armor plate before the discovery of Gundarium Alpha which completely eclipses it.
			</summary>
		</item>
		<item name="Gundarium Alpha">
			<titles>Gundarium, Luna Titanium</titles>
			<summary>
				Originally called Luna Titanium, it was renamed after the success of the RX-78 Gundam built from it.
				A super high-tensile alloy originally known as Luna Titanium.  Originally intended for use inside thermonuclear
				reactors, this alloy's superb strength, durability, heat resistance and radiation-absorbing properties make it
				an ideal material for mobile suit armor.
			</summary>
		</item>
		<item name="Gundarium Gamma">
			<summary>
			</summary>
		</item>
		<item name="60mm Vulcan Cannon" classification="Cannon" modifiers="Auto" muzzlevelocity="1000m/s" rof="220/min" range="8.5km" modifiers="Auto">
			<titles>VCU-505EX-Gry/Ver.009 (Titans) / VCU-505EX-V*B/Ver.012 (AEUG)</titles>
			<reference>Stats based on 57mm Bofors Naval Gun</reference>
		</item>
		<item name="100mm Machine Gun" classification="Cannon" modifiers="Auto" muzzlevelocity="600m/s" modifiers="Auto">
			<titles>NF-GMG-Type.37</titles>
		</item>
		<item name="120mm Machine Gun" classification="Cannon" modifiers="Auto" muzzlevelocity="600m/s" rounds="100" modifiers="Auto" />
		<item name="180mm Recoilless Cannon" classification="Cannon" muzzlevelocity="300m/s">
			<titles>NFHI-GMCa-type.09</titles>
		</item>
		<item name="240mm Recoilless Cannon" classification="Cannon" muzzlevelocity="300m/s" />
		<item name="280mm Bazooka" classification="Hvy. Rocket Launcher" muzzlevelocity="120m/s" rounds="4" modifiers="HE" />
		<item name="360mm Hyper Bazooka" classification="Hvy. Rocket Launcher" muzzlevelocity="120m/s" rounds="10" modifiers="HE">
			<titles>H&amp;L-GB05R (Zeon) / H-Baz-85-Gry/Ver.045 (Titans) / H-Baz-87-A*E/Ver.004 (AEUG)</titles>
			<summary>
				* Capable of destroying a GM in a single hit.
			</summary>
		</item>
		<item name="380mm Hyper Bazooka" classification="Hvy. Rocket Launcher" muzzlevelocity="120m/s" rounds="5" modifiers="HE">
			<titles>BLASH-XHB-L-03/N-STD</titles>
		</item>
		<item name="Clay Bazooka" classification="Hvy. Rocket Launcher" muzzlevelocity="120m/s" modifiers="HE" image="Gundam/ClayBazooka.jpg">
		</item>
		<item name=".4MW Beam Saber" classification="Hvy. Melee" energy="1.2MJ" modifiers="Energy">
			<titles>XB-G-1048L (Titans) / A*E-Br*G-Sc-L (AEUG)</titles>
		</item>
		<item name=".65MW Beam Saber" classification="Hvy. Melee" energy="1.95MJ" modifiers="Energy" />
		<item name="1.3MW Beam Gun" classification="Cannon" energy="3.9MJ" modifiers="Energy" />
		<item name="1.3MW Funnel" classification="Cannon" energy="3.9MJ" modifiers="Energy" />
		<item name="1.9MW Beam Rifle" classification="Cannon" energy="5.7MJ" modifiers="Energy">
			<titles>BOWA-BR-S-85-C2</titles>
			<summary>
				Powered by rechargeable energy cap
			</summary>
		</item>
		<item name="2.2MW Beam Pistol" classification="Cannon" energy="6.6MJ" modifiers="Energy">
			<summary>
				Powered by rechargeable energy cap
			</summary>
		</item>
		<item name="2.2MW Funnel" classification="Hvy. MG" energy="6.6MJ" modifiers="Energy" />
		<item name="2.6MW Beam Rifle" classification="Cannon" energy="7.8MJ" modifiers="Energy">
			<titles>BOWA*XBR-M-86-C2 (Titans), A*E-Br*XBR-87-C (AEUG)</titles>
			<summary>
				Powered by rechargeable energy cap
			</summary>
		</item>
		<item name="2.8MW Beam Rifle" classification="Cannon" energy="8.4MJ" modifiers="Energy">
			<summary>
				Powered by rechargeable energy cap
			</summary>
		</item>
		<item name="5.7MW Beam Rifle" classification="Cannon" energy="17.1MJ" modifiers="Energy" image="Gundam/ZetaBeamRifle.jpg">
			<summary>
				Powered by replaceable e-pac, doubles as large beam saber
			</summary>
		</item>
		<item name="8.3MW Hyper Mega Launcher" classification="Cannon" energy="24.9MJ" modifiers="Energy">
			<summary>
				Powered by replaceable e-pac, doubles as large beam saber
			</summary>
		</item>
		<item name="19.5MW Mega Particle Gun" classification="Cannon" energy="58.5MJ" modifiers="Energy" />
	</section>
</chapter>
<chapter name="Mobile Suit Gundam Units">
	<section name="Gundam Independents">
		<unit name="Side" length="32km" />
	</section>
	<section name="Gundam Federation">
		<unit name="Ball" classification="Cannon" mass="17.2tons" height="12.8m" speed=".96g" image="Gundam/Ball.png">
			<titles>RB-79</titles>
			<summary>
			</summary>
			<skill name="Gunnery" level="3">
				<item name="180mm Recoilless Cannon" facing="F" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Gundam" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="43.4tons" height="18m" image="Gundam/Gundam.png">
			<titles>RX-78-2</titles>
			<summary>
Performance: maximum thruster acceleration 0.93 G; maximum ground running speed 165 km/h
Equipment and design features: re-entry coolant system
Optional hand armaments: BOWA-XBR-M-79-07G beam rifle, powered by rechargeable energy cap;
RXM-Sh-008/S-01025 shield, can be optionally stored on backpack
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
			<skill name="Melee" level="6">
				<item name=".4MW Beam Saber" number="2" />
			</skill>
			<skill name="Gunnery" level="6">
				<item name="60mm Vulcan Cannon" number="2" facing="Turretx2" />
				<item name="380mm Hyper Bazooka" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Gundam Ground Type" classification="Med. Tank" mass="52.8tons" height="18.2m" image="Gundam/GundamGroundType.png">
			<titles>RX-79(G)</titles>
			<reference>
The engineers at Jaburo used spare parts originally manufactured for the RX-78-2 Gundam prototype and built approximately 20 units of a specialized ground combat-model Gundam, the RX-79[G]. Twelve of these units were assigned to the Kojima Battalion stationed in Southeast Asia, particularly to the 04th and 08th MS Teams. Since the RX-79[G]'s were made primarily of spare parts leftover from "Project V," no replacement parts were available. This resulted in hasty field repairs
			</reference>
			<summary>
Speed: 0.71 G
Fixed armaments: multi-launcher, mounted in chest;
2 x X.B.Sa-G-03 beam saber, stored in recharge
racks in legs, hand-carried in use
Optional fixed armaments: RGM-S-Sh-WF/S-00109 shield, mounted on either forearm
Optional hand armaments:
P.B.R-0079/A12 S-000011 beam rifle, powered by rechargeable energy cap;
bazooka gun, clip-fed, 7 rounds per clip;
6-tube missile launcher;
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
			<skill name="Gunnery" level="4">
				<item name="100mm Machine Gun">
					<summary>Clip-fed, 2 spare clips stored on hip armor</summary>
				</item>
				<item name="180mm Recoilless Cannon" />
				<item name="60mm Vulcan Cannon" number="1" facing="FF">
					<summary>Chest Mount</summary>
				</item>
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Guncannon" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="51tons" height="17.5m" speed="78kph" image="Gundam/Guncannon.png">
			<titles>RX-77-2</titles>
			<summary>
Speed: 0.74 G
Optional hand armaments: BOWA-XBR-L beam rifle, powered by rechargeable energy cap
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
			<skill name="Gunnery" level="4">
				<item name="240mm Recoilless Cannon" number="2" rounds="40" facing="FFx2" />
				<item name="60mm Vulcan Cannon" number="2" facing="Turretx2" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Guntank" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="56tons" height="15.6m" speed="70kph" image="Gundam/Guntank.png">
			<titles>RX-75</titles>
			<summary>
				Performance: maximum thruster acceleration 1.10 G; maximum ground driving speed 70 km/h
				2 x 4-tube 40mm rocket launcher, mounted on arms
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
			<skill name="Gunnery" level="4">
				<item name="180mm Recoilless Cannon" number="2" facing="FFx2" rounds="60" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="GM" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="41.2tons" height="18m" image="Gundam/GM.png">
			<titles>RGM-79</titles>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Magellan" classification="Hvy. Spacecraft" image="Gundam/Magellan.png">
		</unit>
		<unit name="Pegasus Class Carrier" classification="Hvy. Spacecraft" mass="54ktons" length="341.7m" width="124.1m" height="76.5m" image="Gundam/WhiteBase.png">
			<titles>White Base</titles>
			<summary>
Fixed armaments: 4 x main gun; 2 x mega particle gun; hyper mega particle cannon; 2 x missile launcher
Mobile suits: 8 (12)
2x Catapults
			</summary>
		</unit>
	</section>
	<section name="Zeon">
		<unit name="Big-Zam" classification="Med. Spacecraft" image="Gundam/BigZam.png">
			<titles></titles>
			<summary></summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Energy" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Dom" image="Gundam/Dom.png">
			<titles></titles>
			<summary>
				Ground Mobile Suit
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Elmeth" classification="Med. Spacecraft" image="Gundam/Elmeth.png">
			<titles></titles>
			<summary></summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Gelgoog" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" image="Gundam/Gelgoog.png">
			<titles></titles>
			<summary></summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Gouf" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" image="Gundam/Gouf.png">
			<titles></titles>
			<summary></summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Rick Dom" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="78.6tons" height="18.6m" image="Gundam/RickDom.png">
			<titles>MS-09R</titles>
			<reference>
				Realizing that the outcome of the war was going to be decided in space, Zeon devoted all of its mobile suit
				manufacturing resources to space combat units.  Refining the Dom design for space was simple, and mostly involved
				replacing the hover jet thrusters with standard rocket thrusters.  Zeon manufacturers began cranking out hundreds
				of these new units late in the war, replacing the aging MS-06F Zaku II as the premiere front line combat unit.
			</reference>
			<summary>
Performance: maximum thruster acceleration 0.67 G; maximum ground running speed 110 km/h
Fixed armaments: scattering beam gun, mounted in torso; heat saber Type7, battery powered, stored in recharge rack on back, hand-carried in use
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
			<skill name="Gunnery" level="4">
				<item name="360mm Hyper Bazooka" rounds="10" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Zaku II" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="58.1tons" height="17.5m" image="Gundam/ZakuII.png">
			<titles></titles>
			<summary>
Speed: .59G/88kph
Sensor radius: 3200 m
180-degree turn time: 1.7 sec
Ground speed: 88 km/h
Armor: super-high tensile steel
Armament: heat hawk x 1
Optional armament: 3-missile pod x 2, cracker
			</summary>
			<skill name="Gunnery" level="3">
				<item name="280mm Bazooka" rounds="4" />
				<item name="120mm Machine Gun" rounds="100" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Z'Gok" classification="Lt. Naval Vessel" mass="65.1tons" height="18.4m" crew="1" image="Gundam/ZGok.png">
			<titles>MSM-07</titles>
			<summary>
0.86 G; maximum water speed 103 knots
Fixed armaments:
6 x 240mm missile launcher, 5 round magazine per launcher, mounted in head;
2 x mega particle cannon, mounted in forearms
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Zeong" classification="Med. Spacecraft" mass="151.2tons" height="17.3m" crew="1" image="Gundam/Zeong.png">
			<titles>MSN-02</titles>
			<summary>
maximum thruster acceleration 0.81 G
Fixed armaments: 2 x wire-guided 5-barrel mega particle gun, barrels mounted in manipulator fingers, all barrels in each hand
are fire-linked; 2 x mega particle gun, mounted in torso; mega particle gun, mounted in head
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Gwazine Class Battleship" classification="Hvy. Spacecraft" mass="108.1ktons" length="440m" width="320m" height="103m" image="Gundam/Gwazine.png">
			<reference>
The Zeon Gwazine class battleships were more than a match for any Federation Forces warship.
			</reference>
			<summary>
Fixed armaments: 3 x 2-barrel main gun; 10 x 2-barrel secondary gun; many x 155mm machine gun
Mobile suits: 20
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Musai" image="Gundam/Musai.png">
		</unit>
		<unit name="Zanzibar Class Cruiser" classification="Hvy. Spacecraft" length="255m" width="221.8m" height="70.5m" image="Gundam/Zanzibar.png">
			<reference>
Zeon's closest answer to the Federation's Pegasus class carrier, the Zeon Zanzibar class mobile cruiser replaced the vulnerable H.L.V. for the purpose of ferrying mobile suits to Earth and back to space. With a capacity of 6 mobile suits and a battery of bow-mounted mega particle guns, the Zanzibar was often used as the command ship for smaller fleets when a Gwazine class battleship was either unavailable or unsuitable. Lacking the Pegasus class' integral Minovsky Craft System, the Zanzibar could only operate for short periods in Earth's atmosphere, using sustained thrust. When being launched back into space, the Zanzibar class required a special rocket booster to supply the necessary thrust to break free of Earth's gravity.
 like most Zeon warships of the One Year War, lacked launch catapults, instead deploying its complement of mobile suits through a simple hatch on the ventral hull.
			</reference>
			<summary>
			Fixed armaments: 1 x 2-barrel main gun; 4 x mega particle gun; 5 x 2-barrel machine gun
Mobile suits: 6
			</summary>
		</unit>
	</section>
	<section name="0083">
		<unit name="Gundam GP01" image="Gundam/GundamGP01.png">
			<titles>Gundam Unit 01</titles>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Gundam GP02" image="Gundam/GundamGP02.png">
			<titles>Gundam Unit 02</titles>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Gundam GP03" image="Gundam/GundamGP03.png">
			<titles>Gundam Unit 03</titles>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Neue Ziel" image="Gundam/NeueZiel.png">
		</unit>
	</section>
	<section name="AEUG">
		<unit name="Z Gundam" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="28.7tons" height="19.8m" image="Gundam/ZGundam.png">
			<titles>MSZ-006</titles>
			<summary>
				* Variable Mobile Suit
Speed: 1.81 G
Fixed armaments:
2 x 2-tube grenade launcher, 2 rounds per tube, mounted in forearms;
Optional fixed armaments:
grenade launcher cartridge, 18+1 rounds, serves as extended ammunition magazine for grenade launcher;
shield, mounted on left forearm
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
				<item name="Gundarium Gamma" />
			</skill>
			<skill name="Melee" level="6">
				<item name=".65MW Beam Saber" number="2" />
			</skill>
			<skill name="Gunnery" level="6">
				<item name="5.7MW Beam Rifle">
					<summary>
						2 spare e-pacs stored in shield
					</summary>
				</item>
				<item name="8.3MW Hyper Mega Launcher" />
				<item name="60mm Vulcan Cannon" number="2" facing="Turretx2" rounds="1200" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Z Gundam Waverider" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="28.7tons" length="24.3m" width="18.6m" speed="1.81g" image="Gundam/Waverider_ZGundam.png">
			<titles>MSZ-006</titles>
			<summary>
				* Variable Mobile Suit
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
				<item name="Gundarium Gamma" />
			</skill>
			<skill name="Gunnery" level="6">
				<item name="5.7MW Beam Rifle" />
				<item name="1.3MW Beam Gun" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="G-Defenser" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="24.7tons" length="39.5m" width="27.1m" speed="1.41g" image="Gundam/GDefenser.png">
			<titles>FXA-05D</titles>
			<summary>
				* Space Fighter
				* Separatable cockpit capsule
Fixed armaments: 2 x 14-tube missile pod, mounted in binders on main body; long beam rifle, mounted on main body; 2 x mini laser gun fire-linked, power rated at 1.7 MW each, mounted in nose of cockpit capsule; 4 x vulcan gun, mounted in pairs in missile pod binders, each pair fire-linked
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Gundam MK-II" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="33.4tons" height="18.5m" speed="1.5g" image="Gundam/GundamMkII.png">
			<titles>RX-178</titles>
			<reference>
				* Paradoxically, the Gundam Mk. II is not armored with the wonderfully durable Gundarium alloy material used by
				the original RX-78 Gundam, making it no more or less physically durable than mass-production mobile suits.
			</reference>
			<summary>
RX*M-Sh-VT/S-00018 (Titans) / RX*M-Sh-VT/S-001 (AEUG) shield, mounted on either forearm
Optional hand armaments: 2 spare e-pacs stored in shield;
AE/ZIM.C-BAZ-531 clay bazooka, clip-fed, 7 rounds per clip
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
			<skill name="Melee" level="5">
				<item name=".4MW Beam Saber" number="2" />
			</skill>
			<skill name="Gunnery" level="5">
				<item name="2.6MW Beam Rifle" />
				<item name="360mm Hyper Bazooka" rounds="7" />
				<item name="60mm Vulcan Cannon" number="2" facing="Turretx2" rounds="1400" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Hyaku Shiki" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="31.5tons" height="18.5m" speed="1.37g" image="Gundam/HyakuShiki.png">
			<titles>MSN-100</titles>
			<summary>
Equipment and design features: anti-beam reflective coating on amror
Optional hand armaments:
AE/ZIM.C-BAZ-531 clay bazooka, clip-fed, 7 rounds per clip; mega bazooka launcher
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
				<item name="Gundarium Alpha" />
			</skill>
			<skill name="Melee" level="6">
				<item name=".4MW Beam Saber" number="2" />
			</skill>
			<skill name="Gunnery" level="6">
				<item name="2.8MW Beam Rifle" />
				<item name="60mm Vulcan Cannon" number="2" facing="Turretx2" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Nemo" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="36.2tons" height="18.5m" speed="1.15g" image="Gundam/Nemo.png">
			<titles>MSA-003</titles>
			<summary>
Optional fixed armaments: shield, mounted on either forearm
Although closely based on the GM II, was far better in performance in terms of generator power,
thruster acceleration and maneuverability. To help keep its cost down, the Nemo used many weapons
already employed by other existing mobile suits, such as the RMS-099 Rick Dias' beam saber and the
GM II's beam rifle.
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
				<item name="Gundarium Alpha" />
			</skill>
			<skill name="Melee" level="3">
				<item name=".4MW Beam Saber" number="2" />
			</skill>
			<skill name="Gunnery" level="3">
				<item name="1.9MW Beam Rifle" />
				<item name="60mm Vulcan Cannon" number="2" facing="Turretx2" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Rick Dias" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="32.2tons" height="18.7m" speed="1.37g" image="Gundam/RickDias.png">
			<titles>RMS-099, Gundam Gamma</titles>
			<reference>
				* Because many former Zeon engineers worked on the Rick Dias, it featured many similaritys to Zeon suits.  It not
				only features a mono-eye sensor its name is also derived from the MS-09R Rick Dom (Rick comes from the word
				Remake).  The Rick Dias should originally be called Gundam Gamma because it is built out of new Gundarium Gamma.
				This material was developed by Axis and it makes the suit lighter and thus makes it able to accommodate greater
				fuel capacity.
			</reference>
			<summary>
				* Equipment and design features: 2 x 'random binder' ejectable external propellant tank, mounted on backpack; birdlime launchers in hands; flare launchers in hands
				* Fixed armaments: 2-barrel 55mm vulcan phalanx anti-missile gun system, mounted in head;
				* Optional hand armaments: AE/ZIM.C-BAZ-531 clay bazooka, clip-fed, 7 rounds; beam rifle, powered by rechargeable energy cap
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
				<item name="Gundarium Gamma" />
			</skill>
			<skill name="Melee" level="5">
				<item name=".4MW Beam Saber" number="1" />
			</skill>
			<skill name="Gunnery" level="3">
				<item name="2.2MW Beam Pistol" number="2" />
				<item name="60mm Vulcan Cannon" number="2" facing="Turretx2" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Super Gundam" classification="Med. Spacecraft" mass="72.9tons" height="18.5m" image="Gundam/SuperGundam.png">
			<titles>FXA-05D+RX-178</titles>
			<summary>
				Combined Mobile Suit
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Argama" classification="Hvy. Spacecraft" image="Gundam/Argama.png">
		</unit>
		<unit name="Garuda Class Transport" classification="Med. Aircraft" mass="9800tons" length="317m" width="524m" image="Gundam/Garuda_Audhumla.png">
			<titles>Audhumla, Garuda, Melord, Sudori</titles>
			<summary>
Propulsion system: jet engine x 10
Armament: laser gun x 10
Mobile suits: 20
Ships of the line: Garuda, Audhumla, Sudori, Melord
Mechanical designer: Kazumi Fujita
			</summary>
		</unit>
	</section>
	<section name="Gundam Titans">
		<unit name="Asshimar" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="41.1tons" height="19.3m" image="Gundam/Asshimar.png">
			<titles>NRX-044</titles>
			<summary>
				* Variable Mobile Suit
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Baund-Doc" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="82.7tons" height="27.3m" image="Gundam/BaundDoc.png">
			<titles>NRX-055</titles>
			<summary>
				* Variable Mobile Suit
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Byalant" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="34.2tons" height="18.6m" image="Gundam/Byalant.png">
			<titles>PMX-000</titles>
			<summary>
				* Variable Mobile Suit
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Gabthley" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="32.6tons" height="18.5m" image="Gundam/Gabthley.png">
			<titles>RX-110</titles>
			<summary>
				* Variable Mobile Suit
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Gaplant" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="50.7tons" height="19.8m" image="Gundam/Gaplant.png">
			<titles>ORX-005</titles>
			<summary>
				* Variable Mobile Suit
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="GM II" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="40.5tons" height="18.1m" speed="1.06g" image="Gundam/GMII.png">
			<titles>RMS-179, RGM-79R</titles>
			<summary>
Fixed armaments:
beam saber, power rating unknown
Optional fixed armaments: shield, mounted on either forearm
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
			<skill name="Gunnery" level="3">
				<item name="1.9MW Beam Rifle" />
				<item name="60mm Vulcan Cannon" number="2" facing="Turretx2" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Hambrabi" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="34.6tons" height="19.9m" image="Gundam/Hambrabi.png">
			<titles>RX-139</titles>
			<summary>
				* Variable Mobile Suit
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Hizack" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="38.7tons" height="18m" image="Gundam/Hizack.png">
			<titles>RMS-106</titles>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Marasai" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="33.1tons" height="17.5m" image="Gundam/Marasai.png">
			<titles>RMS-108</titles>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Messala" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="37.3tons" height="23m" image="Gundam/Messala.png">
			<titles>PMX-000</titles>
			<summary>
				* Variable Mobile Suit
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Psycho-Gundam" classification="Med. Spacecraft" mass="214.1tons" height="40m" image="Gundam/PsychoGundam.png">
			<titles>MRX-009</titles>
			<summary>
				* Variable Mobile Suit
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Energy" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Psycho-Gundam MK-II" classification="Med. Spacecraft" mass="187.8tons" height="40m" image="Gundam/PsychoGundamMkII.png">
			<titles>MRX-010</titles>
			<summary>
				* Variable Mobile Suit
Performance: maximum thruster acceleration: 0.86 G (mobile suit mode), 1.99 G (mobile fortress mode)
Equipment and design features: sensors, range 16230 meters; psycho control chair in cockpit; detachable head, can be operated without main body
Fixed armaments: 20 x mega beam gun, power rated at 6.3 MW each, 3 mounted in each shoulder, 4 mounted in each leg, 2 mounted in each hip armor, 1 mounted in each front waist armor; 3 x mega scattering beam gun, power rated at 10.7 MW each, mounted in torso; 2 x wire-guided psycommu beam sword, power rated at 1.7 MW each, mounted in forearms; 10 x beam gun, emitter barrels mounted as fingers in hands; 2-barrel mega beam gun, mounted in head
Remote weapons: reflector bits, deflects and redirects beam weapons fire, stored in backpack
Though armed with the same 3-barreled scattering mega particle gun in its chest and beam gun fingers, the Psyco Gundam Mark II also mounted 20 smaller beam guns all over its body, giving it firepower capable of attacking targets in all directions. Its forearms also mounted large-bladed beam swords, and could be detached and directed at targets via a cable connection and through the control of the Psyco Gundam Mark II's psycommu system, giving the unit an all-range attack capability quite similar to that of the Principality of Zeon's MSN-02 Zeong. The Psyco Gundam Mark II also carried a set of 'reflector bits,' which were unarmed but used to redirect its own beam weapons fire to targets that are out-of-sight, or to deflect incoming enemy beam weapons fire.
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Energy" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Qubeley" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="35.2tons" height="18.4m" speed="1.08g" image="Gundam/Qubeley.png">
			<titles>AMX-004</titles>
			<summary>
Fixed armaments: 2 x beam launcher/beam saber, mounted in forearms in beam launcher mode, hand-carried in beam saber mode
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
			<skill name="Gunnery" level="6">
				<item name="1.3MW Funnel" number="10" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="The-O" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="57.3tons" height="24.8m" speed="1.57g" image="Gundam/TheO.png">
			<titles>PMX-003</titles>
			<summary>
4 x sub-arm, mounted inside front skirt armor
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
			<skill name="Melee" level="6">
				<item name=".4MW Beam Saber" number="4" />
			</skill>
			<skill name="Gunnery" level="6">
				<item name="2.6MW Beam Rifle" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Saberfish" classification="Lt. Aircraft" image="Gundam/Saberfish.png">
			<summary>
				High Altitude Fighter
			</summary>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Gwazine" image="Gundam/Gwazine.png">
		</unit>
		<unit name="Jupitris" image="Gundam/Jupitris.png">
		</unit>
		<unit name="Salamis" image="Gundam/Salamis.png">
		</unit>
	</section>
	<section name="Federation (New)">
		<unit name="Nu Gundam" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="27.9tons" height="22m" image="Gundam/NuGundam.png">
			<titles>RX-93</titles>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Re-GZ" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="24.7tons" height="20.5m" image="Gundam/ReGZ.png">
			<titles>RGZ-91</titles>
			<summary>
				* Variable Mobile Suit
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
	</section>
	<section name="Neo Zion">
		<unit name="Alpha-Azieru" classification="Med. Spacecraft" mass="267.4tons" length="108m" height="58.4m" image="Gundam/AlphaAzieru.png">
			<titles>NZ-333</titles>
			<summary>
Speed: 8.29 G
				* 2 x external propellant tank, ejectable, mounted on main body
Fixed armaments: 2 x wire-guided psycommu mega arm, each mounts 5 x beam gun, fire-linked, power rated at 12.6 MW each
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
			<skill name="Gunnery" level="6">
				<item name="19.5 MW Mega Particle Gun" facing="Turret" />
				<item name="2.2MW Funnel" number="9" />
				<item name="60mm Vulcan Cannon" number="4" facing="Turretx4" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
		<unit name="Sazabi" classification="Lt. Spacecraft" mass="30.5tons" height="25m" image="Gundam/NuGundam.png">
			<titles>MSN-04</titles>
			<skill name="Armor">
				<ability name="Hardened vs. Projectiles" />
			</skill>
		</unit>
	</section>
</chapter>
<chapter name="Terminator">
	<section name="Terminator Units">
		<unit name="Terminator T-800" mass="200kg" image="Terminator/T800.png">
			<skill name="Armor" />
			<skill name="Strength" />
		</unit>
		<unit name="Terminator T-1000" image="Terminator/T1000.png">
			<skill name="Armor" />
			<skill name="Strength" />
			<skill name="Natural Weaponry" />
			<skill name="Flexible" />
		</unit>
		<unit name="Terminator T-X" mass="150kg" image="Terminator/TX.png">
			<summary>
				* The T-X is designed to not only terminate humans but rogue Terminators
				reprogrammed by the Resistance. It is a composite of the T-800 and T-1000,
				a solid endoskeleton covered with polymimetic liquid metal alloy, allowing
				it to take the shape of any humanoid it touches. The T-X endoskeleton
				contains many powerful weapons making it considerably more deadly than
				previous versions.
			</summary>
			<skill name="Armor" />
			<skill name="Gunnery" />
			<skill name="Strength" />
			<skill name="Natural Weaponry" />
		</unit>
		<unit name="Terminator Hunter Killer" image="Terminator/HunterKiller.png">
			<skill name="Armor" />
			<skill name="Gunnery" />
		</unit>
		<unit name="Terminator Tank" image="Terminator/HKTank.png">
			<skill name="Armor" />
			<skill name="Gunnery" />
		</unit>
	</section>
</chapter>
</doc>
